<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Texan Mason]]></title><description><![CDATA[A Millennial in the Quarries, Yelling into the Void]]></description><link>http://texanmason.com</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 21:48:41 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://texanmason.com/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[Lone Star Masonry (Special Guest: Robert Marshall)]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="__em_pre_recorded_sam_obiturary_em"><em>Pre-Recorded: Sam Obiturary</em></h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Details: <a href="http://www.greenwoodfuneralhomes.com/obituaries/Sam-Levisee/#!/Obituary" class="bare">http://www.greenwoodfuneralhomes.com/obituaries/Sam-Levisee/#!/Obituary</a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="__em_intro_music_w_disclaimer_em"><em>Intro Music w/ Disclaimer</em></h2>
<div class="sectionbody">

</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_host_and_guest_introductions">Host and Guest Introductions</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Remember to rattle off your Blue Lodge titles, y&#8217;all.</p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Rhit</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Grant</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Gabe</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>"and we have a special guest today&#8230;&#8203;"</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p>Robert</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="__em_pre_recorded_masonic_news_for_week_of_tomorrow_s_release_em"><em>Pre-Recorded: Masonic News for Week of Tomorrow&#8217;s Release</em></h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_temple">Temple</h3>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>We had a great stated meeting this Monday. We had 46 or so brothers attend, including a sizable contingent from Oklahoma. We would like to extend our special thanks to them and an extra special thanks to Right Worshipful Deputy Grand Master Corky Grigsby the pleasure of hosting him! Our special congratulations to Brother Namon Kouri, worshipful master of Frederick Lodge #249 under the jurisdiction of the Grand Lodge of Oklahoma. Brother Kouri&#8217;s mother lodge is Fort Worth Lodge, and although he had to relocate to Oklahoma, he was able to come down for his 25-year pin! So once again, congrats Brother Kouri. In light of Brother Sam Levisee&#8217;s passing onward and upward into the pearly gates, instead of Masonic education that night, each one of us that knew Sam stood up and told a story about him. It was beautiful. Not a dry eye in the place.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_local">Local</h3>

</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_state">State</h3>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://lonestarmason.wordpress.com/2017/07/07/masonic-improvement-the-chamber-of-refraction/">Go check out the blog Lone Star Mason by Brother Justin Jones.</a> I&#8217;ve been on a real kick of reading different blog posts by "local" guys, so to speak, ever since Brother Lance Kennedy wrote his <em>10 Propositions for Texas Freemasonry</em>. It seems like there&#8217;s been an increase in writing, sharing, and reading masonic blog posts since that. Anyway, Brother Justin put up a great piece on the Lone Star Mason blog called <em>The Chamber of Refraction</em>, in which he talks about some of the common problems he&#8217;s encountered in the anteroom in which candidates are prepared for degrees. I highly recommend it. Check Brother Justin out at lonestarmason.wordpress.com.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_national">National</h3>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/freemasonry/comments/6mr4ul/posted_on_brother_andrew_hammers_facebook_page/?st=j51azesu&amp;sh=accae4b7">Alexandria-Washington Lodge #22, Grand Lodge of Virginia, AF&amp;AM</a> - Brother Andrew Hammer, former Worshipful Master of Alexandria-Washington, has demitted from his lodge, and as such, is no longer a Mason under the jurisdiction of the Grand Lodge of Virginia, and is not under charges or on suspension there. He&#8217;s still a Mason in a few other jurisdictions, so if you were planning on having him come speak at your lodge, you&#8217;ll still be fine. His situation with his Grand Lodge has been resolved, and we wish Brother Hammer the best of luck in his future endeavors.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://www.jsonline.com/story/news/crime/2017/07/03/lawyers-seek-release-man-charged-16-months-ago-plotting-foiled-machine-gun-attack-milwaukee/424399001/">Milwaukee, WI</a> - there&#8217;s some more news on the attempted attack on the Scottish Rite Temple in Milwaukee. About a year and a half ago, this guy called Samy Hamzeh was arrested by the FBI on two counts of possessing an illegally-acquired fully-automatic firearm and one count of possessing an illegally-acquired suppressor. He&#8217;s looking at up to 30 years in prison for this. However, now it&#8217;s come out that he bought those from undercover FBI agents, and interestingly enough, he was talked into preparing the attack by FBI informants. One of the informants, called "Mike," is the one who specifically introduced Masons into the equation, telling Hamzeh that Masons were affiliated with ISIS and that Masons were the enemy of Islam and ate human hearts. Now, Hamzeh and his lawyers are pushing for a case of entrapment. Supposedly, the audio transcripts of the phone calls reveal that for a long time, Hamzeh actually repeatedly rejected the ideas that were being pushed on to him. Obviously, this case is still in development, and we&#8217;ll update y&#8217;all as we learn more.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://www.cincinnati.com/story/news/2017/07/07/anti-trump-graffiti-suspect-indicted/457103001/">Colerain Township, OH</a> - a man is being held on bail after being arrested for two counts of misdemeanor criminal damaging. This guy, Avery Collins, graffittied buildings and cars at two businessess with anti-Trump and anti-Masonic graffiti. He wrote things like "Kill Free Masons," "Kill Freemasons ASAP," and "Black Lifes matter Bitches Burn Trump with all Crackers." Pretty scary stuff - take care out there, brothers. By the way, to the conspiracy theorists and/or anyone wondering: I&#8217;d like to point out that Masons aren&#8217;t affiliated with any one politician, or any one party.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_international">International</h3>

</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_listener_discussion_questions">Listener/Discussion Questions</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Quick question with quick answer: I was told if you have tattoos you can&#8217;t be a mason. True or nay?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Discussion question: Does your lodge have any resident ghosts?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_episode_content">Episode Content</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Special Guest: Robert Marshall</p>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_standard_guest_questions">Standard Guest Questions</h3>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Can you tell us about yourself in a nutshell?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>When did you join the Craft?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What inspired you to join?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Which lodge did you join at first, and what drew you to them?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What do you think of your experience while going through the degrees?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Can you tell us a little bit about your lodge?</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>History</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Stated Meeting dates/times</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Floor School dates/times</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p>What officer positions have you held in the past?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What is your favorite aspect of Masonry, and why?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What do you think are the strengths and weaknesses of Masonry in Texas? (or "your state" if guest is a Mason outside of TX)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>How do you see the overall state of Masonry in Texas? (or "your state" if guest is a Mason outside of TX)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What do you think we need to do to improve?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What keeps you motivated to keep working in the quarries?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_questions_for_robert">Questions for Robert</h3>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>What draws you to research history?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What are some good resources to research history, especially Masonic history, which can be so obscure sometimes?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Who do you recommend for brothers to look into for research purposes, and why?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>How can researching history help a lodge?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>How do you prefer to share your research?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What are your favorite Masonic history stories?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Waco #92 recently digitized its minutes. Can you tell us more about that project?</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>What recommendations do you have for lodges that are looking at doing that?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Now that the project is done, what would you have done differently?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p>How much digital tech do y&#8217;all use for meetings? iPads for sign-ins, computers for secretaries, stenography, etc.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>You&#8217;re the brand-new secretary. What challenges are you looking at in your new role?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What&#8217;s something that you want to try doing in your lodge that you haven&#8217;t tried yet?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>How can we better manage our social media presence as Masons, Lodges, and as a fraternity?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What appendant bodies are you involved in, and do you have any cool stories, historical or otherwise, about them?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What do you think about the idea of eBooks for ciphers and rituals?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What&#8217;s something y&#8217;all are doing in Waco #92 that you think other lodges should do?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What&#8217;s something you have seen in other lodges that you&#8217;d like to implement in Waco #92?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Let&#8217;s time-travel to the future. Your great-great-grandson is writing a history book about Masonry in that long passed era of the 2010s and 2020s. What is he writing about you, your lodge, and Texan Masonry?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What&#8217;s a jurisdiction that you&#8217;d like to learn more about?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Are there any historical subjects where you are stuck at a dead-end? (no leads, info, etc)</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>More (or fewer) questions at the discretion of guest and hosts.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="__em_pre_recorded_events_for_week_of_tomorrow_s_release_em"><em>Pre-Recorded: Events for Week of Tomorrow&#8217;s Release</em></h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Brothers, it&#8217;s July. That means that somewhere, near you, a lodge is having their installation of officers. Go to it! Support your local lodges. Heck, if you have travel, go support some non-local lodges! Leadership is a challenge and having people show up to welcome you into it is very reassuring.</p>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_national_2">National</h3>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/freemasonry/comments/6mojj6/battleship_new_jersey_degree/?st=j51aycqe&amp;sh=e7a1958e">July 25</a> - The Rough Ashlars of New Jersey are putting on a Master Mason&#8217;s degree on the USS New Jersey in Camden, New Jersey. Tickets to the degree are $10 and proceeds go towards the upkeep of teh USS NJ. This event is for master masons only, and the dress code is Hawaiian shirts and slacks. Please look them up on eventbrite (E V E N T B R I T E DOT COM).</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_state_2">State</h3>

</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_local_2">Local</h3>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>August 12 - Thomas B Hunter Lodge #1356 in Grand Prairie will be hosting the Julian Feild Players! The Players will be putting on the play, "A Rose Upon the Altar"  on Saturday, August 12, from 10 AM to noon. "A Rose Upon the Altar" is a play about a Lodge in 1939 that is struggling financially and trying to figure out how to keep their lodge going, and continue the chairty work that the community needs. The event is open to the public. I didn&#8217;t see any admission prices, and it&#8217;s listed as "free to all," but since lunch will follow the play, I would personally urge y&#8217;all to bring a little donation to help offset the costs of hospitality.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_temple_2">Temple</h3>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>July 17 &amp; 18 - Texas Chapter is putting on the Mark Master, Virtual Past Master, and Most Excellent Master degrees! The Mark Master degree will take place on the 17th and the VPM &amp; MEM degrees will take place on the 18th. Both events will be in the Red Room at 6:30 PM. If you are a Royal Arch Mason, please join us!</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>If you are planning on attending Brother Sam Levisee&#8217;s funeral, the services will take place at 1:30 PM on this Friday the 14th of July, at the Greenwood Chapel, and interment will follow in Greenwood Memorial Park. You can find Greenwood Chapel at 3100 White Settlement Road in Fort Worth.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>As always, Fort Worth Lodge #148 meets on the second Monday of each month. Dinner is at 6 PM, and our meeting is at 7 PM.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_closing_thoughts_on_episode_content">Closing Thoughts on Episode Content</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Max 2 min/person, except guests.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_quote">Quote</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="quoteblock">
<blockquote>
<a href="http://freemasoninformation.com/2013/12/a-interview-with-arturo-dehoyos/">I believe that my role is to preserve and disseminate Masonic light and knowledge. One of the things I’ve tried to do is publish and/or write books which I wish had existed when I was a younger Mason. It was well-nigh impossible to find some of the things I’ve published when I was younger.</a>
</blockquote>
<div class="attribution">
&#8212; Illustrious Brother Arturo de Hoyos<br>
<cite>33° Grand Cross of Honor, Grand Archivist & Grand Historian of the Supreme Council 33° of the Ancient & Accepted Scottish Rite, Southern Jurisdiction, USA.</cite>
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>(Rattle off contact info for lodge, let any guests plug their websites/contact info, then sign off.)</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="__em_contact_info_em"><em>Contact Info</em></h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><em><a href="http://www.fortworth148.org/" class="bare">http://www.fortworth148.org/</a></em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>@fortworthlodge148 on Facebook</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>info148@fortworth148.org</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>If you live in the 64th district of the Grand Lodge of Texas and want to promote an event, please reach out to them at 64th.org - SIX FOUR TEE AITCH DOT ORG</em></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>http://texanmason.com/2017/07/13/Lone-Star-Masonry-Special-Guest-Robert-Marshall.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://texanmason.com/2017/07/13/Lone-Star-Masonry-Special-Guest-Robert-Marshall.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Jewel P Lightfoot Lodge (Special Guest: David Bindel)]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="__em_intro_music_w_disclaimer_em"><em>Intro Music w/ Disclaimer</em></h2>
<div class="sectionbody">

</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_host_and_guest_introductions">Host and Guest Introductions</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Remember to rattle off your Blue Lodge titles, y&#8217;all.</p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Rhit</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Grant</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Gabe</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>"and we have a special guest today&#8230;&#8203;"</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p>David</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="__em_masonic_news_for_week_of_tomorrow_s_release_em"><em>Masonic News for Week of Tomorrow&#8217;s Release</em></h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>To be recorded!</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_listener_discussion_questions">Listener/Discussion Questions</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Is being a great leader and running a great lodge the same thing?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_episode_content">Episode Content</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Special Guest: David Bindel</p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Tell us about yourself in a nutshell!</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Who has been the biggest influence for you in Masonry?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What problems do you see with Masonry?</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>What&#8217;s the biggest problem out of the ones you&#8217;ve listed?</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>What is JPL doing to fight this?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What should other lodges do to solve this?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p>What is JPL&#8217;s lodge culture like?</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>What kind of brother would feel really at home there?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p>What does JPL excell at as a lodge?</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>What do you feel JPL needs to work on?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p>How does it feel now to be free as the Junior Past Master?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What was the project you were proudest of during your year as Worshipful Master?</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>What was something you wish had worked out better?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p>What&#8217;s an ongoing, multi-year project y&#8217;all have got going?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What&#8217;s the newest project that you like, or something you want to see get targeted?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>How do you develop talent in others or help them to grow to the next level?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What&#8217;s your strategy for good financial health as a lodge?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Let&#8217;s say things are going badly for a lodge. Low membership, running ragged financially, all that jazz. What should they do? Redesign, merge, etc?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>How compatible is Masonry in general with modern culture?</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>How compatible is Masonry (as practiced in JPL &amp; other TO lodges) with modern culture?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p>Where do you see Masonry in 25 years?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Where do you see JPL in 25 years?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>How long does it take brothers to go from initiation to proficient Master Masons in JPL?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>How do you determine proficiency?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>How do you encourage regular attendance at stated meetings and degrees?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>How big should a lodge be?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Exactly how strictly should we be guarding the west gate?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What charity efforts is JPL involved in?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Can you tell us about your festive boards and/or table lodges?</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>What&#8217;s the key to a big event like that?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p>What big educational pushes have y&#8217;all been working on?</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Should lodges have education at every stated meeting, or try to make stateds shorter by having seperate nights for education?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Assuming the Bible is the first thing on the list, what else should be on every brand new master mason&#8217;s reading list?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p>What do you look for in officers?</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>What&#8217;s your take on the progressive line?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p>What&#8217;s the dress code for JPL if we want to visit?</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Should more lodges adopt dress codes?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What about dress codes at more lax levels than suit and tie (example, encouraging business casual, but discouraging BOTH underdressing and overdressing)</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p>Do y&#8217;all use music during degrees?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Do y&#8217;all use a chamber of reflection?</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>What&#8217;s in it?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p>What&#8217;s your best memory in the Craft?</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>What&#8217;s your funniest memory in the Craft?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="__em_events_for_week_of_tomorrow_s_release_em"><em>Events for Week of Tomorrow&#8217;s Release</em></h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>to be recorded!</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_closing_thoughts_on_episode_content">Closing Thoughts on Episode Content</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Max 2 min/person, except guests.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_quote">Quote</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="quoteblock">
<blockquote>
<a href="http://www.masonicrestorationfoundation.org/documents/What-Are-We-Trying-To-Save.pdf">The quality of the Craft must not be permitted to continue to decline. We must
recognize that the organization is much larger than the combination of all of its
component parts. We say we are a Brotherhood of Men under the Fatherhood of God, a
Fraternity designed to make good men better. If this is what we are trying to save, we
should reexamine our approach. If we make good men better, we succeed in the purpose of the Craft, and these
better men will then continue to lead the world. If we fail, the whole world loses [&#8230;&#8203;</a> ]
</blockquote>
<div class="attribution">
&#8212; RW Thomas W. Jackson<br>
<cite>What Are We Trying to Save?</cite>
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>(Rattle off contact info for lodge, let any guests plug their websites/contact info, then sign off.)</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="__em_contact_info_em"><em>Contact Info</em></h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><em><a href="http://www.fortworth148.org/" class="bare">http://www.fortworth148.org/</a></em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>@fortworthlodge148 on Facebook</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>info148@fortworth148.org</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>If you live in the 64th district of the Grand Lodge of Texas and want to promote an event, please reach out to them at 64th.org - SIX FOUR TEE AITCH DOT ORG</em></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>http://texanmason.com/2017/06/28/Jewel-P-Lightfoot-Lodge-Special-Guest-David-Bindel.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://texanmason.com/2017/06/28/Jewel-P-Lightfoot-Lodge-Special-Guest-David-Bindel.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Fraternal Spotlight - Corey Harris]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="__em_intro_music_w_disclaimer_em"><em>Intro Music w/ Disclaimer</em></h2>
<div class="sectionbody">

</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_host_and_guest_introductions">Host and Guest Introductions</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Remember to rattle off your Blue Lodge titles, y&#8217;all.</p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Rhit</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Grant</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Gabe</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>"and we have a special guest today&#8230;&#8203;"</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p>Corey</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="__em_masonic_news_for_week_of_tomorrow_s_release_em"><em>Masonic News for Week of Tomorrow&#8217;s Release</em></h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>To be recorded!</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_listener_discussion_questions">Listener/Discussion Questions</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>What non-principal, non-progressive line, officer role do you want to see take a bigger stage in your lodges?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_episode_content">Episode Content</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Special Guest: Corey Harris</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_general_questions">General Questions</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>These can be either "Craft" or "Life in General," if seperate answers, ask the interviewee for both.</p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Who has been the most important or influential person to you?</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Can you tell us about them?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>How did they influence you?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p>What has been your happiest moment?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What has been your saddest moment?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What&#8217;s the most important lesson you&#8217;ve learned?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What are you proudest of?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>How would you like to be remembered?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Where did you grow up?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_general_craft_questions">General Craft Questions</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>These are more specifically-oriented towards the Masonic experience of the interviewee.</p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Which Mason, living or dead, would you like to sit down and talk with for an hour?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>How would you describe yourself?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Did you have any (maybe even many!) Masonic relatives?</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Did you have any favorites?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="sect3">
<h4 id="_leadship">Leadship</h4>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>How does it feel to be a brand-new Worshipful Master?</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>You&#8217;re Arlington&#8217;s youngest worshipful Master in the history of the lodge. How does <em>that</em> feel?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What&#8217;s your list of top three, top five things to get done this year?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Are there any ongoing or in-progress projects that you&#8217;ll be continuing as worshipful master?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect3">
<h4 id="_looking_back">Looking Back</h4>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>What&#8217;s the funniest thing that you&#8217;ve seen in Lodge?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>If you forgot all of your Masonic experiences except one, what would that one be?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Is there something that you wish you&#8217;d done differently on your journey so far?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What&#8217;s something that you&#8217;d say to your past self right after your EA degree?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Is there a time when you thought about leaving the Craft, or that Masonry was just kind of difficult to enjoy?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect3">
<h4 id="_looking_forwards">Looking Forwards</h4>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>What&#8217;s on the horizon for you and your Masonic career?</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Beyond the horizon?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p>What are your hopes for what the future holds for the newest generation of Masons?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Disregarding hopes, what are predictions (optimistic/pessimistic) for 5, 10, 20 years from now?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What&#8217;s something you want to say to your great-great-grandson after his EA degree?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect3">
<h4 id="_regular_vocations">Regular Vocations</h4>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Can you tell us a little about what you do for a living?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>How well does that "play" with Masonic time commitments?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Have you had any cool run-ins with Brothers via work?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What lessons has Masonry provided you that have been helpful to your work experience?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect3">
<h4 id="_that_whole_religion_thin">That Whole "Religion" Thin</h4>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>As a Mason, you definitely believe in some form of higher power, but can you tell us a little bit more specifically about your spiritual and/or religious beliefs?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_aye_laddy">AYE, LADDY</h3>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Can you tell us about your involvement in Scottish Rite?</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>In that vein, can you tell us about your experience with the knights of Saint Andrew?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>KoSA is a often cited as a great leadership experience. What lessons for KoSA are you applying, or have applied, to your Blue Lodge leadership strategies?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="__em_events_for_week_of_tomorrow_s_release_em"><em>Events for Week of Tomorrow&#8217;s Release</em></h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>To be recorded!</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>As always, Fort Worth #148 meets on the Second Monday of each month, starting dinner at 6PM for a 7PM stated meeting at 1100 Henderson Street, Fort Worth, Texas</em></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_closing_thoughts_on_episode_content">Closing Thoughts on Episode Content</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Max 2 min/person, except guests.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_quote">Quote</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="quoteblock">
<blockquote>
<a href="https://en.wikiquote.org/wiki/Theodore_Roosevelt#Quotes">There are two things that I want you to make up your minds to: first, that you are going to have a good time as long as you live – I have no use for the sour-faced man – and next, that you are going to do something worthwhile, that you are going to work hard and do the things you set out to do.</a>
</blockquote>
<div class="attribution">
&#8212; Brother President Theodor Roosevelt<br>
<cite>in a Christmastime talk to some schoolchildren.</cite>
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>(Rattle off contact info for lodge, let any guests plug their websites/contact info, then sign off.)</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="__em_contact_info_em"><em>Contact Info</em></h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><em><a href="http://www.fortworth148.org/" class="bare">http://www.fortworth148.org/</a></em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>@fortworthlodge148 on Facebook</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>info148@fortworth148.org</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>If you live in the 64th district of the Grand Lodge of Texas and want to promote an event, please reach out to them at 64th.org - SIX FOUR TEE AITCH DOT ORG</em></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>http://texanmason.com/2017/06/25/Fraternal-Spotlight-Corey-Harris.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://texanmason.com/2017/06/25/Fraternal-Spotlight-Corey-Harris.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[06/22/2017 Show Notes - Quarryman's Roundtable (Special Guest: Brad Billings)]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="__em_intro_music_w_disclaimer_em"><em>Intro Music w/ Disclaimer</em></h2>
<div class="sectionbody">

</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_host_and_guest_introductions">Host and Guest Introductions</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Remember to rattle off your Blue Lodge titles, y&#8217;all.</p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Rhit</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Grant</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Gabe</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>"and we have a special guest tonight&#8230;&#8203;"</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p>Brad</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="__em_masonic_news_for_week_of_tomorrow_s_release_em"><em>Masonic News for Week of Tomorrow&#8217;s Release</em></h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In anticipation of a long episode, we will be omittting news.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_listener_discussion_questions">Listener/Discussion Questions</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>How do you feel about lodges going dark for the summer?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What do you think about the idea of establishing an evaluation for officers in order to give them <em>constructive</em> advice for the next year?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What books are on y&#8217;all&#8217;s nightstands right now?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_episode_content">Episode Content</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Special Guest: Brad Billings</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://texanmason.com/notes/20170621-extra-resume.html">Brad&#8217;s Masonic Resume</a></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_general_questions">General Questions</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>These can be either "Craft" or "Life in General," if seperate answers, ask the interviewee for both.</p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Who has been the most important or influential person to you?</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Can you tell us about them?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>How did they influence you?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p>What has been your happiest moment?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What has been your saddest moment?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What&#8217;s the most important lesson you&#8217;ve learned?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What are you proudest of?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>How would you like to be remembered?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Where did you grow up?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_general_craft_questions">General Craft Questions</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>These are more specifically-oriented towards the Masonic experience of the interviewee.</p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Which Mason, living or dead, would you like to sit down and talk with for an hour?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>How would you describe yourself?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Did you have any (maybe even many!) Masonic relatives?</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Did you have any favorites?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="sect3">
<h4 id="_leadship">Leadship</h4>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>What officer positions (Blue Lodge, Grand Lodge) do you currently hold?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>You were raised in Trinity Valley Lodge #1048 and then got to be Master of the Lodge during its Centennial year. How did that feel?</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>What are you most proud of accomplishing during your year in the East there?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What&#8217;s something you didn&#8217;t quite get to that you&#8217;d love to see another Worshipful try and tackle?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p>How are you liking this whole DDGM thing?</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>What led to you becoming a DDGM?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p>What led you to becoming the Grand Junior Steward, and what were your responsibilities as that Grand Officer?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>You&#8217;ve been a charter member and/or charter officer of a lodge, a research society, a chapel, and an assemblage.</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>What are the challeges of chartering an organization?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What was that like for you?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Would you be interested in tackling something like that again?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect3">
<h4 id="_looking_back">Looking Back</h4>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>What&#8217;s the funniest thing that you&#8217;ve seen in Lodge?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>If you forgot all of your Masonic experiences except one, what would that one be?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Is there something that you wish you&#8217;d done differently on your journey so far?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What&#8217;s something that you&#8217;d say to your past self right after your EA degree?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Is there a time when you thought about leaving the Craft, or that Masonry was just kind of difficult to enjoy?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect3">
<h4 id="_looking_forwards">Looking Forwards</h4>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>What&#8217;s on the horizon for you and your Masonic career?</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Beyond the horizon?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p>What are your hopes for what the future holds for the newest generation of Masons?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Disregarding hopes, what are predictions (optimistic/pessimistic) for 5, 10, 20 years from now?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What&#8217;s something you want to say to your great-great-grandson after his EA degree?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>How do you think we can ensure that we&#8217;re a sustainable organization?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>In that vein, do we really have a membership problem?</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>If we don&#8217;t, what has caused that perception?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>If we do, what do you think caused it?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect3">
<h4 id="_making_it_work">Making it Work</h4>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>What&#8217;s your strategy for time management?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What&#8217;s your strategy for learning new material, and/or revisiting old material?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What&#8217;s been the most difficult thing about your level of involvement?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Do you have any advice for younger guys who are still learning the family/vocation/Craft balance?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect3">
<h4 id="_regular_vocations">Regular Vocations</h4>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Can you tell us a little about what you do for a living?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>How well does that "play" with Masonic time commitments?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Have you had any cool run-ins with Brothers via work?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What lessons has Masonry provided you that have been helpful to your work experience?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect3">
<h4 id="_that_whole_religion_thing">That Whole "Religion" Thing</h4>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>As a Mason, you definitely believe in some form of higher power, but can you tell us a little bit more specifically about your spiritual and/or religious beliefs?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Texas requires Masons to believe in "the existence of God, the immortality of the soul, and the Divine authenticity of the Holy Scripture." Most Grand Jurisdictions require less, a small number require more. What are your thoughts on this?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Have you ever had someone approach you with religiously-oriented (or otherwise) anti-Masonry?</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>What was your response/reaction?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_the_appendant_body_rabbit_hole">The Appendant Body Rabbit-hole</h3>
<div class="sect3">
<h4 id="_just_a_quick_dip_in_the_water">Just a quick dip in the water</h4>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>What current officer positions do you hold in the appendant bodies you belong to?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What&#8217;s your favorite petitionable appendant body?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What&#8217;s you favorite invitational appendant body?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect3">
<h4 id="_aye_laddy">AYE, LADDY</h4>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Can you tell us about your experience in Scottish Rite?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Pretend that none of the rest of us know about Scottish Rite. What&#8217;s the deal with the different colored hats, and why do you wear a red one?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What are the Knights of Saint Andrew?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>How do degree teams in Scottish Rite work?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What do you do as a Chairman of the Ambassadors for the Membership Committee?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What do you want to tell interested, but not yet involved, Master Masons, about Scottish Rite?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect3">
<h4 id="_in_the_quarries">In the Quarries</h4>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Can you tell us about your experience in Chapter &amp; Council?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>How was your experience as High Priest &amp; Thrice Illustrious Master of Love Field Chapter &amp; Council?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Unlike Scottish Rite, York Rite seems to be having a tough go of it and it seems to hit Chapters &amp; Councils the hardest. What do you think is the key to revitalizing these two bodies?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Some brothers like them, others don&#8217;t; what&#8217;s your opinion on Festivals?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>How has your experience as a District Deputy difference in Grand Chapter, Grand Council, and Grand Lodge?</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>What led you becoming a district deputy for Chapter and district deputy for Council?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p>What&#8217;s the key to having an impactful year as a High Priest &amp; Thrice Illustrious Master?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What do you want to tell interested, but not yet involved, Master Masons, about Chapter &amp; Council?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect3">
<h4 id="_taco_hats_jesus">Taco Hats &amp; Jesus</h4>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Can you tell us about your experience in Commandery?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>How was your experience as Eminent Commander?</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Any favorite moments, events, or impacts that you made?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p>How, and how well, has Commandery complimented your faith?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Like the other bodies we&#8217;ve talked about, what&#8217;s your Commandery elevator speech?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect3">
<h4 id="_invitational_bodies_elevator_speech_lightining_round">Invitational Bodies - Elevator Speech Lightining Round</h4>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Knights of the York Cross of Honor</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Allied Masonic Degrees</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>York Rite College</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Knight Masons</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The Commemorative Order of Saint Thomas of Acon</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Royal Order of Scotland</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The WSFMRMWSPPB (The Operatives)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Holy Royal Arch Knight Templar Priests</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Societas Rosicruciana in Civitatibus Foederatis</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect3">
<h4 id="_invitational_bodies_actual_questions">Invitational Bodies - Actual Questions</h4>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>You definitely dedicated some time to AMD and are now a Past Sovereign Master. What is it about AMD that called you to leadership there?</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>What has been your favorite experience in AMD?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Is AMD intended to have a larger impact on Masonry as a whole, or is it more of a quiet preservation effort? (I&#8217;m not sure if this is the right question to ask, actually)</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p>You helped charter Odessa Chapel #18 for the Commemorative Order of Saint Thomas of Acon. Can you tell us some more about that?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What&#8217;s the story behind your name, Brother Alchemy, in the Royal Order of Scotland, and why do brothers pick names in the Order?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Can you tell us more about the Worshipful Society of Free Masons, Rough Masons, Wallers, Slaters, Paviors, Plaisterers, and Bricklayers, better known as the Operatives?</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Can you tell us about chartering the San Jacinto Monument Assemblage?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p>You were recently invested with the VII° Adeptus Exemptus (7th Grade, Adeptus Extremus) in the Texas College of SRICF. What does that mean in terms of responsibilites? Is that like recieving a degree for knowledge, or is that a chair degree?</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Do you have any recommendations for people who are looking to learn more about Rosicrucianism, or any book recommendations on Rosicrucian teachings?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p>In your opinion, should Masonic invitational bodies be more restrictive, or less restrictive?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="__em_events_for_week_of_tomorrow_s_release_em"><em>Events for Week of Tomorrow&#8217;s Release</em></h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In anticipation of a long episode, we will be omittting events.</p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><em>As always, Fort Worth #148 meets on the Second Monday of each month, starting dinner at 6PM for a 7PM stated meeting at 1100 Henderson Street, Fort Worth, Texas</em></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_closing_thoughts_on_episode_content">Closing Thoughts on Episode Content</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Max 2 min/person, except guests.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_quote">Quote</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="quoteblock">
<blockquote>
<a href="https://play.google.com/books/reader?id=pu45AQAAIAAJ&amp;printsec=frontcover&amp;output=reader&amp;hl=en&amp;pg=GBS.PA43">When I am employed in serving others, I do not look upon myself as conferring favors, but as paying debts. I have received much kindness from men to whom I shall never have an opportunity of making the least direct returns; and numberless mercies from God, who is infinitely above being benefited by our services. Those kindnesses from men I can, therefore, only return on their fellow-men, and I can only show my gratitude for those mercies from God by a readiness to help His other children.</a>
</blockquote>
<div class="attribution">
&#8212; Right Worshipful Brother Benjamin Franklin<br>
<cite>May 17th entry in Poor Richard Day by Day</cite>
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>(Rattle off contact info for lodge, let any guests plug their websites/contact info, then sign off.)</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="__em_contact_info_em"><em>Contact Info</em></h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><em><a href="http://www.fortworth148.org/" class="bare">http://www.fortworth148.org/</a></em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>@fortworthlodge148 on Facebook</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>info148@fortworth148.org</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>If you live in the 64th district of the Grand Lodge of Texas and want to promote an event, please reach out to them at 64th.org - SIX FOUR TEE AITCH DOT ORG</em></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>http://texanmason.com/2017/06/21/Podcast-Brad-Billings.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://texanmason.com/2017/06/21/Podcast-Brad-Billings.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Elevator Speeches]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>There will come a time when you need to explain what the heck Masonry is. Sometimes, you won&#8217;t have very long. It&#8217;s best to come up with an "elevator speech" for those occasions. My answer is a little dramatic:</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><em>The world is an awful place, and there&#8217;s not much that we can do about that on the macro scale. What we can do,  however, is give men the opportunity to change and improve themselves using moral tools and teachings in order to better implement the moral values they already had. By doing this, a man not only changes himself, but the world immediately around him - and sometimes reaching even further than that. So, we can&#8217;t change the world on a macro scale, but we can change it many, many times on a micro scale.</em> <strong><em>Masonry is an organized effort to save the world, one man at a time.</em></strong></p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://texanmason.com/2017/06/20/How-to-Explain-Masonry-in-30-Seconds-or-Less.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://texanmason.com/2017/06/20/How-to-Explain-Masonry-in-30-Seconds-or-Less.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Freemason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Free]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Masonry]]></category><category><![CDATA[Craft]]></category><category><![CDATA[Blue]]></category><category><![CDATA[Lodge]]></category><category><![CDATA[Elevator]]></category><category><![CDATA[Speech]]></category><category><![CDATA[Quick]]></category><category><![CDATA[Explanation]]></category><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Funding a Lodge from the Ground Up - V∴I∴ Jason Mitchell]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div id="preamble">
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p><em>This was all originally written by V∴I∴ Brother Jason Mitchell in the comments of <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/freemasonry/comments/5vrtmu/dues_are_getting_so_expensive/?st=j3oth0wz&amp;sh=f9963ca6">this post</a>. All I&#8217;ve done is format it for easier sharing - many thanks to Brother Mitchell for writing this in the first place.</em></p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Funding a Lodge/Organization is something that is important to me. I&#8217;ve started a Mark Lodge, two AMD Councils, a Black Hat Club, an SRICF College, and been part of the planning for bodies for Athelstan and Acon.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In all that time, I&#8217;ve seen:</p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>seven ways to incorrectly fund a an emerging Masonic body;</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>seven ways to incorrectly fund a brand new Masonic body;</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>and at least a dozen incorrect ways to continue funding an established body.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Unlike your existing Lodges, the ability to see and take a Masonic organization from idea, to conception, to charter, to sustaining, and probably death, in the case of the Mark Lodge, has been fascinating, because I&#8217;d argue less than 1% of masons have ever seen a Masonic organization established from the ground up.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>For me, it comes down to this: I don&#8217;t care about your sentimental attachments to your (misquoted) ritual, I don&#8217;t care about your statistical outliers of that one guy who is great but broke, etc.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><em>I care about funding an organization that is self-sustaining, at least financially, for two, or three, or four generations in advance - with the foresight that there will be expenses and needs thenk, that I cannot even conceive of now. By that, I mean try explaining powered light to someone in the 18th century, or websites and online payments to someone in the 1950s, and so forth.</em></p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>For me the measure of success, regardless of the actual dollar amount, is that all money coming into the Lodge today, is spent 30, 40, or 50 years from now. The paycheck-to-paycheck cash flow (if you can honestly call it that) is wrong. We are living, we&#8217;re barely sustaining - it&#8217;s scarcity survival.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>What that does mean for Masons today, is whatever that dollar amount is that it takes to fund your Lodge as is, double it - at least - so you&#8217;re putting money back into the bank.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Use the following formula to find out what you need to get the Lodge off the ground:</p>
</div>
<div class="quoteblock">
<blockquote>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><em>Initial Funding</em> = <em>(Total funding from Part 1)</em> + <em>(Three times the double of the total from Part 2)</em></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>or</p>
</div>
<div class="quoteblock">
<blockquote>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><em>Initial Funding</em> = <em>P1</em> + 6(<em>P2</em>)</p>
</div>
</blockquote>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>This will give you everything you need to get the Lodge off the ground, and three years of projected operational costs in the bank. There should be no further purchases to kit out the Lodge, and all the money coming into the Lodge is spent at a later time. If you never spend more than 80% of your income (no zero-sum budgeting), then as a function of time, you will be growing financially.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><em>Oh, and most importantly - <strong>build in an exit strategy!</strong> Determine <strong>now</strong>, not later, financial performance thresholds that automatically trigger closing the lodge.</em></p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Part III is suggested on-going operational assumptions.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_part_i_getting_started_outfitting">Part I: Getting Started - Outfitting</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Here is where you decide, "do I want a solid gold apron, or is a shiny brass one enough, or do I want shiny plastic?" You need to determine:</p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>what it will cost to legally establish the body, be it fees to the sponsoring/chartering masonic body, legal fees (if incorporation is necessary), bank fees, etc&#8230;&#8203;</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>the total price to outfit the body. Using a Lodge, and assuming you have a building to meet in, and that building has chairs already, that means everything: from aprons to altars, to rods, to jewels, to patents, to ballot boxes, to ritual books - I mean literally everything. You&#8217;ll want at least one of everything, possibly two on things that may wear or get dirty.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>prices for boxes to securely store and transport all those things in, unless the building comes with storage, but even then, boxes help protect them in storage, so it&#8217;s good to have.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>if you need to insure these effects against loss or damage, and if so, and it requires a down payment, get that number too.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>the total price on all administrative tools: Dues cards, folders, paper clips, pens/pencils, laptop, printer, paper, ink, filing cabinets, desk, pens, envelopes, postage, business/calling cards, website, accounting software, etc - <em>everything the Secretary, Master, and Wardens will materially need to have in their possession for their job</em> (bearing in mind, we&#8217;re not talking about having 100 pencils for Brothers who suddenly need one in Lodge).</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_part_ii_get_going_operational">Part II: Get Going - Operational</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Don&#8217;t go cheap here. Don&#8217;t try to cut corners. Again, you want real costs for real results. <em>This will be expensive.</em></p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>What is the total cost of rents for the year? Stated and Special meetings, Educationals, Officer meetings, Everything.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Are there dining costs the Lodge must absorb? Example: will there be refreshments at officer meetings? If so, there is an operational cost.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What is the cost of education and training? What books and materials will you need to have for the first 36 months to fully train and prepare candidates, and officers, into Masonry, and the culture of the Lodge? Does your GL require officers to participate in any training/course, etc? This is one of the first places we start cheating ourselves and others. Prepare for the future. Is digital truly equivalent to physical for a new candidate?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Do candidates get patents and/or presentation Bibles? You&#8217;ll need a supply on hand. What is your expected number of EA, FC, and MM?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What other materials will Candidates receive from the Lodge, to commemorate their Initiation, Passing, and Raising, if any? Again, another number.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What is the total cost for Lodge communication to members? I&#8217;d argue you need physical mailing, plus at least two other forms of communication (email, social media, texting, etc).</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_part_iii_preparing_for_the_worst_and_other">Part III: Preparing for the Worst and Other</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Always put 10% of your income into long term savings.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Always set aside an additional 10% of your income as a buffer for a given fiscal year to cover cost overruns. Unused portions should go into long term savings.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Assume you&#8217;ll never receive any money for degree fees.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Assume you&#8217;ll have 30% voluntary dues compliance <strong>before</strong> the due date.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Assume you&#8217;ll have an additional 20% within 60 days following the due date.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Assume you&#8217;ll receive an additional 30% dues compliance with costs, 12 months late.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Never assume more than 80% total dues compliance after any length of time.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Always match your dues to a firmly establish economic indicator: DOW, COLA, etc., something. Increase dues constantly.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Never, ever, ever, ever, take cash.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Always take credit card payments - never pass on the processing fees, that&#8217;s a cost of doing business these days.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Take ACH payments.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Take EFT payments.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Take checks.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>http://texanmason.com/2017/06/08/Funding-a-Lodge.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://texanmason.com/2017/06/08/Funding-a-Lodge.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Freemason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Free]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Masonry]]></category><category><![CDATA[Craft]]></category><category><![CDATA[Blue]]></category><category><![CDATA[Lodge]]></category><category><![CDATA[Bodies]]></category><category><![CDATA[Finances]]></category><category><![CDATA[Starting]]></category><category><![CDATA[Group]]></category><category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category><category><![CDATA[Jason Mitchell]]></category><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[06/07/2017 Show Notes (Dues, Dues, Dues)]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="__em_intro_music_w_disclaimer_em"><em>Intro Music w/ Disclaimer</em></h2>
<div class="sectionbody">

</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_host_and_guest_introductions">Host and Guest Introductions</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">

</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="__em_masonic_news_for_week_of_tomorrow_s_release_em"><em>Masonic News for Week of Tomorrow&#8217;s Release</em></h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="__em_temple_em"><em>Temple</em></h3>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><em>The Knights of Saint Andrews of the Fort Worth Scottish Rite Valley have new members! On Wednesday night, five true Masons because five good knights when they had the Order of the Thistle conferred upon them. Congrats!</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>Texas Chapter #362 &amp; Texas Council #321 had their officer elections on Tuesday night! Congrats to our officers-elect! List is as follows:</em></p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong><em>Texas Chapter #362, Royal Arch Masons</em></strong></p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><em>High Priest   -   Robert Trevathan</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>Excellent King   -   James Jones</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>Excellent Scribe   -   Bruce Hammond, PHP</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>Treasurer   -   V∴E∴ Steve Wolfe, PGHP</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>Secretary   -   Neal Addy, PHP</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>Captain of the Host   -   S. Kenneth Griffin, PHP</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>Principal Sojourner   -   Henry Hash, PHP</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>Royal Arch Captain   -   David Kisselburg, PHP</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>Master of the Third Veil   -   William Nash</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>Master of the Second Veil   -   Gabriel Jagush</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>Master of the First Veil   -   Robert Cooke</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>Guard   -   Philip Valdez</em></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong><em>Texas Council #321, Royal &amp; Select Masters</em></strong></p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><em>Thrice Illustrious Master   -   Robert Trevathan</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>Right Illustrious Deputy Master   -   James Jones</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>Illustrious Principal Conductor of the Work   -   Bruce Hammond, PTIM</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>Treasurer   -   V∴I∴ Steve Wolfe, PGM</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>Recorder   -   Neal Addy, PTIM</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>Chaplain   -   Henry Hash, PTIM</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>Captain of the Guard   -   S. Kenneth Griffin, PTIM</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>Conductor of the Council   -   David Kisselburg, PTIM</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>Steward   -   Gabriel Jagush</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>Sentinel   -   Philip Valdez</em></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="__em_local_em"><em>Local</em></h3>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><em>Haltom City / Riverside Lodge #1331 had a really eventful stated meeting! They had a scholarship presentation night with over 70 Masons, Eastern Star Sisters, and welcome vistors present. 18 visitors from  Fort Worth Lodge and Crowley Lodge were also present, with Crowley Lodge successfully taking the travelling gavel!</em></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="__em_texas_em"><em>Texas</em></h3>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><em>(No news this week.)</em></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="__em_national_em"><em>National</em></h3>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><em>COLUMBUS, Ohio - the Northland Masonic Temple has once again been the target of vandalism. Last week, they got hit by bright blue spray-paint graffiti on the back of their lodge and on their front sign. They took a couple of days, cleaned everything up, and began to resume life as normal. It wasn&#8217;t long before the sign was vandalized again. Fortunately, the vandal was witnessed in action, and arrested by police after they managed to stop his vehicle later on. It is believed that the same vandal is behind both incidents. Best of luck, brothers. Maybe it&#8217;s time to invest in cameras and a dog!</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>PORTAGE, Wisconsin - Fort Winnebago Lodge #33 had to call in a tow truck from Blystone&#8217;s Towing in order to move their safe! Apparently it was quite the amusing sight. The brothers from Fort Winnebago Lodge are moving down the block to a new temple and had to get some help with the 1-ton safe. Can&#8217;t say we blame them! Best of luck with the rest of the move, brothers.</em></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="__em_abroad_em"><em>Abroad</em></h3>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><em>Oslo, Norway - My apologies in advance, as I&#8217;m going off of Google Translate due to neither speaking Dansk nor Norshk. a 67-year-old man is being charged with attempted extortion. The victims? One of the lodges that meet in the Freemason&#8217;s Hall at 23 Blegdamsvej in Copenhagen, Denmark. He had filmed their some of their degrees and/or meetings and attemptted to extort them to the tune of 33 million Danish kroener, which is about 5 million USD. My understanding is that this occurred in the Danish Freemason&#8217;s Hall over the period of January 2016 to November 2016, and while I&#8217;m not a 100% clear on the translation, it seems that he may have tried this in April 2017 with a Norwegian lodge, or he may have made the threats of extortion from Norway to Denmark at that time, I&#8217;m not sure. It&#8217;s not clear as to whether or not the man was a member of the fraternity, but fortunately it sounds like the charges are for attempted extortion, not successful extortion. The perpetrator has now been extradited to Denmark after being held in Norway following his arrest in Oslo. Best of luck to our Dansk brothers in having a little justice laid down.</em></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_questions">Questions</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>I ride motorcycles, can I join the widow&#8217;s sons? Not in Texas, not since 2007.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Advice for those with a really long commute to their lodge?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Other than the Bible, what&#8217;s the most important book to your Masonic experience?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_episode_content">Episode Content</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_rhit_s_notes">Rhit&#8217;s Notes</h3>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Arguments:</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>This isn&#8217;t fair to guys on fixed incomes.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Old guys who can&#8217;t afford it will leave.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Young guys who can&#8217;t afford it won&#8217;t join.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>It&#8217;s morally wrong to charge more than the lodge needs in order to run a net zero?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>It&#8217;s not fair to hold country lodges to the same standards as city lodges?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Some guys are too proud to ask for help.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The minimum dues set by Grand Lodge are perfectly fine.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Grand Lodge has millions in Charity Funds.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Solutions:</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Endowments return 5% on a good year. It&#8217;s time to look at other investment ideas.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Hold fundraisers for your lodge, not just for charity.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Remit dues or freeze rates for retirees.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Present the proposal for a dues increase in a palatable manner.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_gabe_s_throwaway_notes">Gabe&#8217;s throwaway notes:</h3>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Adjusting for inflation &amp; conversions from pounds to dollars, George Washington paid somewhere between $400 &amp; $450 dollars for his degree fees.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://www.masonicdictionary.com/dues2.html">Dues That Don&#8217;t Anymore</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://www.masonicdictionary.com/european.html">Lodge Epicurian</a></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="__em_events_for_week_of_tomorrow_s_release_em"><em>Events for Week of Tomorrow&#8217;s Release</em></h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="__em_texas_em_2"><em>Texas</em></h3>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><em>June 9th &amp; 10th - Texas AMD Day is in Waco this weekend! If you&#8217;re a member of an AMD council here in Texas, please come by. TAMDA will be accepting on-site registration for $20. The group photo will be taken at 8:45 AM on Saturday, for which tuxedos are preffered. They&#8217;ll be conferring ten degrees, including the Masonic Order of the Bath after the AMD Council is closed. M∴ W∴ Grand Master Jerry Nelson Kirby will be the keynote speaker. Sounds like a great time!</em></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="__em_north_texas_tarrant_county_em"><em>North Texas &amp; Tarrant County</em></h3>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><em>June 9th - Arlington Lodge #438 is presenting the Golden Trowel Award to Past Master Bruce Dalton on Friday! A light dinner will be held at 6:30 PM with the trowel ceremony to follow. Arlington Lodge is located at 1415 West Abram Street in Arlington, Texas. You may RSVP to <a href="mailto:daltonfamily@sbcglobal.net">daltonfamily@sbcglobal.net</a> or 817-223-1471.</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>June 11th - the funeral services for Brother Steve Shipe, Past Master of Arlington #438, will be held on Sunday, June 11th at the Moore Funeral Home, which is located at 1219 North Davis Road in Arlington. Please arrive at 12:30, and remember to bring your apron and wear a dark suit.</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>June 16th - Arlington Lodge #438 is having a fish fry for family night! Dinner is at 7 PM.</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>June 17th - on Saturday the 17th, the El Texa Chapter of The Grotto is having their Information Event and Dinner. Drinks are at 6:30 PM and dinner is at 7 PM. The location will be the Elks Lodge of 3233 White Settlement Road in Fort Worth. Please RSVP by June 10th and contact Prophet Buford Young at 817-709-6637.</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>June 23rd - Bolivar Masonic Lodge is hosting their third annual clay shoot! Registration is at 8 am, start is at 9 am, the location is Fossil Pointe Sporting Grounds at 7282 North Farm Road 51 in Decatur, TX. The event will be organized into four-person teams at $100  per person. Lunch is provided. Trophy belt buckles will be awarded to the highest overall team score and the highest overall individual score. 1st, 2nd, and 3rd place teams will receive trophies. Station sponsorship fees at $150 per station. Ear and eye pro are required and you must bring your own ammo. Please send your registration to Bolivar Masonic Lodge before May 23rd.</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>_June 23rd - the brothers of New Day Lodge #655 are holding their "REAL FATHERS, REAL MEN, SOUL FOOD EXPERIENCE" fundraiser event! They will be providing chef-made, tasty meals, to-go. Each meal is packaged in a re-heatable container for ease of preperation and serving. If you are located in the DFW area, they will deliver the menu items to your door at a date and time of your choosing. The event is happening all weekend of June 23rd, so they will be taking orders until 8 PM on the 24th and delivering until 5 PM on the 25th. They are offering babyback ribs, barbecue chicken wings, meat combos, taters, beans, cole slaw, sauce from scratch, and banana pudding. They have individual plates and family meals that feed up to six. They are taking preorders NOW, so please reach out to them at <a href="http://www.newdaylodgepha655.org/">http://www.newdaylodgepha655.org/</a> and put in an order! The brothers from New Day encourage you to join in on the "REAL FATHERS, REAL MEN, SOUL FOOD EXPERIENCE" and warn you "SLEEP LATE, LOSE WEIGHT." _</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>June 26th - River Oaks lodge is having their installation! Brother Sam Levisee is being installed at the age of one hundred years old. Most Worshipful Grand Master Jerry Kirby will be presiding over the installation and the Tarrant County Commandery Standard Guuard will be presenting the American and Texan flags. The meal will be at 6 PM and the installation will begin at 7 PM. Fort Worth Lodge&#8217;s very own Senior Warden, soon to be Worshipful Master, Greg Wright, will be smoking the barbecue. Please join us in welcoming our favorite centenarian, Brother Sam, to the Oriental Chair!</em></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="__em_temple_1100_henderson_street_in_fort_worth_em"><em>Temple - 1100 Henderson Street in Fort Worth</em></h3>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><em>June 19th - Texas Chapter #362 will be conferring the Royal Arch Mason degree on three worthy Most Excellent Masters. If you are a Royal Arch Mason, please come and join us! It will be great. One of my favorite degrees.</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>June 24th - Fort Worth Lodge #148 will be hosting its installation! If you are a friend or family memember of a Fort Worth Lodge member, and are interested in attending, please talk to us.</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>June 27th - Texas Chapter &amp; Council will be having an open installation of officers! We will be kicking off at 6:30 PM in the Red Room on the 3rd floor of the temple. I will be installed as the [OFFICER TITLE HERE] of Texas Chapter and the [OFFICER TITLE HERE] of Council.</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>As always, Fort Worth #148 meets on the Second Monday of each month, starting dinner at 6PM for a 7PM stated meeting at 1100 Henderson Street, Fort Worth, Texas</em></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_closing_thoughts_on_episode_content">Closing Thoughts on Episode Content</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Max 2 min/person, except guests.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_quote">Quote</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="quoteblock">
<blockquote>
<a href="http://www.masonicdictionary.com/european.html">A high quality lodge must be paid for, therefore dues need to commensurate with this.</a>
</blockquote>
<div class="attribution">
&#8212; Lodge Epicurian (Pioneer European Concept lodge of Australia)<br>
<cite>The First Pillar of Lodge Epicurian</cite>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="__em_contact_info_em"><em>Contact Info</em></h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><em><a href="http://www.fortworth148.org/" class="bare">http://www.fortworth148.org/</a></em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>@fortworthlodge148 on Facebook</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>info148@fortworth148.org</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>If you live in the 64th district of the Grand Lodge of Texas and want to promote an event, please reach out to them at 64th.org - SIX FOUR TEE AITCH DOT ORG</em></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>http://texanmason.com/2017/06/07/Podcast-Dues-Dues-Dues.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://texanmason.com/2017/06/07/Podcast-Dues-Dues-Dues.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Destroying the 24-Inch Gauge]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>It&#8217;s been kind of a crazy period of time. Lately, I&#8217;ve been really stretching the limits of my 24-inch gauge. I am really enjoying it, but it&#8217;s not easy. I love pouring my efforts into all things, especially Masonry, but I definitely need to make sure I take personal time now and then.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I&#8217;ve done a less than stellar job of balancing friend groups. There&#8217;s more than a few friends who I think about every once in a while and realize, "wow, [X] and I haven&#8217;t hung out in a while." I&#8217;ve been pretty good about keeping the vast majority of my commitments, but the problem, I feel, now lies in actually arranging those commitments to begin with.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>It&#8217;s very easy to keep commitments when they&#8217;re at lodge. That&#8217;s where I&#8217;m expected to be, and where I enjoy being. It is a breeze to be there! Having a central location to do stuff makes things very easy. I feel like right now we are also in a huge busy season right now. We&#8217;ve had a bunch of raisings and plan on having another one soon, followed by at least one passing, and at least two initiations. There are many brothers in need of instruction, and many ritual parts to be learned.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I feel like I arguably don&#8217;t sleep enough. I usually feel like I&#8217;m super busy, and that&#8217;s why I go to bed so late even though I have to wake up early. That also seems like a ridiculous excuse to try and cover up a severe lack of discipline. Maybe one of these days, I&#8217;ll figure it out.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>On a more positive note, the Commandery Orders were incredible. This was last month, on the 15th. We had/were a bunch of candidates. I really enjoyed the Order of the Red Cross. The story behind it was really entertaining in both a serious and a light-hearted way. The Order of Malta kind of threw me for a loop, though. It felt like it was super-packed with information that just flew by at astronomical speeds. I will have to sit down with a copy of the ritual and a highlighter in order to properly "unpack" all of that.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I was privileged enough to be the exemplar candidate for the Order of the Temple. I have never experienced anything quite so mind-blowing in terms of ritual. There were parts where I had to keep myself from laughing, parts where I was deeply moved, and parts where my heart was pounding, ready to leap out of my chest in excitement and awe. I once heard the OOT described as "everything you ever thought a Masonic degree would ever be," and I have to say, that&#8217;s not wrong. Oddly, I wouldn&#8217;t describe it as "life-changing," as I have heard before. This experience profoundly resonated with emotions and convictions that I have held for a while now. There is no course in direction - if anything, there is now only fuel added to the fire in the engine. IN HOC.</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://texanmason.com/2017/05/04/gabe-is-starting-to-feel-it.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://texanmason.com/2017/05/04/gabe-is-starting-to-feel-it.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Freemason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Free]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Masonry]]></category><category><![CDATA[York]]></category><category><![CDATA[Rite]]></category><category><![CDATA[Knight]]></category><category><![CDATA[Knights]]></category><category><![CDATA[Templar]]></category><category><![CDATA[Malta]]></category><category><![CDATA[Red]]></category><category><![CDATA[Cross]]></category><category><![CDATA[Chivalric]]></category><pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Royal & Select Master Degrees]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>Wow, what a wild ride. I had been given some "hints" regarding the Council degrees, but I still wasn&#8217;t prepared. The Royal Master degree in particular was very beautiful! The solemnity of the soliloquiy gave me shivers. There&#8217;s a lot that I would like to discuss, but unfortunately most all of that is stuff that I can&#8217;t talk about publicly! It was a great experience and I&#8217;m still digesting it, so to speak.</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://texanmason.com/2017/04/12/Royal-amp-Select-Master-Degrees.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://texanmason.com/2017/04/12/Royal-amp-Select-Master-Degrees.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Freemason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Free]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Masonry]]></category><category><![CDATA[Cryptic]]></category><category><![CDATA[Council]]></category><category><![CDATA[Royal]]></category><category><![CDATA[Select]]></category><category><![CDATA[Masters]]></category><category><![CDATA[York]]></category><category><![CDATA[Rite]]></category><pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Instruction Certification & Royal Arch Degree]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>Well, it seems that I finally went and got myself official. As of Saturday (the 25th), I am officially certified by the Grand Lodge of Texas to teach the memory work for degree proficiencies, and the opening of all four lodges (the fourth being the Lodge of Sorrows).</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Initially, I drove all the way to Phoenix Lodge in Weatherford. When I got there, just before the forum (degree exemplification and general Q&amp;A) at 9 am, I was asked, "Hey brother! Are you here for the Commandery Work Day?" My confusion must have beeen pretty evident. I quickly explained that I was there for the exam certification, and was then told that it had been postponed to next weekend. The paper copy of the schedule posted up in the dining hall had been the same one as on the PDF I had on my phone; however, the paper version had a correction on it, in pen. The PDF, naturally, did not have this change.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>At this point, I settled in the hallway, hanging out with some brothers I knew and some brothers that I didn&#8217;t know, chit-chatting about memory work, Commandery, and a few other things. One brother pointed out to me that Krum (and therefore Krum Lodge&#8217;s certification exams) was only an hour and fifteen minutes away. If I hustled, I might still be able to catch the last 20 minutes of the forum, and make it in time for the certification exams.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>So I hustled!</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I managed to get to Krum Lodge and had a great time. I met some District Instructors, members of the Committee on Work, and all sorts of other brothers. One brother had even heard of the podcast that I put out with some of my lodge brothers! The exams went well, and when I left, I was officially "C-certified."</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Last night (Monday, March 27) was also pretty eventful. I managed to double-book myself for both Blue Lodge and Royal Arch Chapter. We had four profiencies in two different degrees in Blue Lodge, and I had my Royal Arch degree scheduled! I had to excuse myself before the last EA profiency, because it was time to go to Chapter. I was really bummed about that, because I am usually the examiner during proficiencies, and I was really looking forwards to this Brother delivering his work.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The Royal Arch degree was absolutely incredible. It was incredibly immersive and I&#8217;m still digesting it. I am looking forwards to the next time - when I can participate in it. I would write more about it, but to be quite honest, I have to let it settle a bit before I can competently talk about it! It&#8217;s got to be one of my favorite degrees so far, though. I might actually like the experience of this one as an initiate even more than the Master&#8217;s degree (although the Entered Apprentice degree still remains my favorite). This was a very physically-involved sort of experience, which I thought was awesome.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Super happy with my experience. I even bought a RAM emblem to put on my car! Very psyched to see what happens in Cryptic Council.</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://texanmason.com/2017/03/28/Instruction-Certification-amp-Royal-Arch-Degree.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://texanmason.com/2017/03/28/Instruction-Certification-amp-Royal-Arch-Degree.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Freemason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Free]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Masonry]]></category><category><![CDATA[Craft]]></category><category><![CDATA[Capitular]]></category><category><![CDATA[Royal]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arch]]></category><category><![CDATA[Chapter]]></category><category><![CDATA[York]]></category><category><![CDATA[Rite]]></category><category><![CDATA[Instruction]]></category><category><![CDATA[Certificate]]></category><category><![CDATA[Certification]]></category><pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sixth Podcast Episode]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>I&#8217;m actually not sure that I posted the fifth episode of the podcast here. Not a huge deal since that&#8217;s an automatic deal! Here is the sixth episode.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>On this week&#8217;s fireside chat, Brothers Rhit Moore, Grant Gates, and Gabriel Jagush are joined by a special guest: Brother Junior Warden Will Weir of Fort Worth #148! Brother Will is the head of the 148 degree team. What are the benefits of a degree team? Who needs to get involved? How should you approach running and maintaining a team? D&#8217;ya got a fancy look? These questions and more get tackled in this episode as Will gives us some insight. Thanks for listening!</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Main discussion starts at around 11:37 and local events listing starts at 1:29:30.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><a href="http://fortworth148.libsyn.com/006-the-art-of-the-degree-team"><em>The Art of the Degree Team</em></a></p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://texanmason.com/2017/03/23/Sixth-Podcast-Episode.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://texanmason.com/2017/03/23/Sixth-Podcast-Episode.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Freemason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Free]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Masonry]]></category><category><![CDATA[Craft]]></category><category><![CDATA[Blue]]></category><category><![CDATA[Lodge]]></category><category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category><category><![CDATA[Fort]]></category><category><![CDATA[Worth]]></category><category><![CDATA[148]]></category><pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Advanced to the Mark Master Degree!]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>Today I was advanced to the degree of Mark Master Mason! I was one of three candidates. It was a fun and interesting experience. The degree team did a great job despite having a bunch of peoople missing - those filling in did very admirably. There was joviality (something very strange compared to my Blue Lodge experience) and quiet, solemn moments. Overall, it was a pretty wonderful time. Next stop: Virtual Past Master and Most Excellent Master!</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://texanmason.com/2017/03/14/MMM-delicious.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://texanmason.com/2017/03/14/MMM-delicious.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Freemason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Free]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Masonry]]></category><category><![CDATA[Craft]]></category><category><![CDATA[Royal]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arch]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mark]]></category><category><![CDATA[Master]]></category><category><![CDATA[Chapter]]></category><category><![CDATA[York]]></category><category><![CDATA[Rite]]></category><pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Handley Lodge Captures the Travel Gavel]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>Where the magic happens:</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://texanmason.com/images/20170313-temple.jpg" alt="20170313 temple.jpg">
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Last night was pretty great!</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Fort Worth Lodge had its stated meeting night, and I was pleasantly surprised to see so many visitors - at first only minorly so, then majorly so. I shared the elevator with three or four brothers from Handley Lodge on the way up to our dining hall&#8230;&#8203; Then I quickly realized, as the time went on, that they were coming out in force! Our little dining hall was packed. Handley Lodge brought out 15 brothers to come help take the travel gavel.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The Grand Lodge of Texas (AF&amp;AM) 64th District Traveling Gavel:</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://texanmason.com/images/20170209-img1.jpg" alt="20170209 img1.jpg">
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The room was abuzz with excitement. Many of the Fort Worth Members were whispering to each other over the food - cooked on the Fort Worth Lodge #148 Smoker, of course - as we were and are totally psyched to get so many visitors. I pro-tem&#8217;d the Senior Deacon&#8217;s part, and began running around the dining hall, collecting names and titles as fast as I could.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The time to file into the lodge room came, and we ran out of aprons! We had to dig in the closet for a third box of aprons. We had a total attendance of 54 brothers. Once visitors were introduced, all first time visitors were given a Fort Worth Lodge pin.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>One of my little treasures, the Fort Worth Lodge #148 pin that was given to me the night that I was raised:</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://texanmason.com/images/20170313-pin.jpg" alt="20170313 pin.jpg">
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>We blasted through the regular business, with some minor delays during a slightly more free-form portion of lodge, and then got to the presentation of the Travel Gavel. Unfortunately, I don&#8217;t have pictures of that, since we were in open lodge at the time (meaning photography is verboten), but it was wonderful. In addition to the travel gavel on the plaque, Fort Worth Lodge has decided to toss in the Mega Gavel as well. Now, in addition to the <a href="http://www.64th.org/traveling-gavel-rules/">existing stipulations</a> on the gavel, the Mega Gavel will be travelling with the regular plaque. After our <a href="http://www.handonahkur.com/">Brother Hando Nahkur</a> played a very stirring piece, we closed out and Hollywooded for the camera. All in all, a great night in Texas Masonry.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>A group photo (most of us are in here):</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://texanmason.com/images/20170313-group.jpg" alt="20170313 group.jpg">
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>14 of the 15 brothers from Handley, with guest appearance by the Mega Gavel (Worshipful Master of Handley Lodge, Haskell Rogers III, is in the middle with the plaque):</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://texanmason.com/images/20170313-handley.jpg" alt="20170313 handley.jpg">
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Our pro-tem WM Greg Wright (on the left) poses with some of our brothers from Webb Lodge! We really hope that they are the next ones to get the gavel. Ed (on the right) is a Past Master of both Webb Lodge and Handley Lodge:</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://texanmason.com/images/20170313-webb.jpg" alt="20170313 webb.jpg">
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Life is good.</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://texanmason.com/2017/03/13/Handley-Lodge-Captures-the-Travel-Gavel.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://texanmason.com/2017/03/13/Handley-Lodge-Captures-the-Travel-Gavel.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Freemason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Free]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Masonry]]></category><category><![CDATA[Craft]]></category><category><![CDATA[Blue]]></category><category><![CDATA[Lodge]]></category><category><![CDATA[Handley]]></category><category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category><category><![CDATA[Gavel]]></category><category><![CDATA[Fraternity]]></category><category><![CDATA[Competition]]></category><pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Fourth Podcast Episode]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>Please join us this week in our fireside chat as we talk about what it means to walk and act as a Mason. What&#8217;s the deal with charity? How to you make sure that you&#8217;re still in touch with your morals? How do we apply the idea of the cornerstone of a building to ourselves? Brothers Rhit Moore, Grant Gates, and Gabriel Jagush get wonderfully sidetracked for a bit on news and then get to work (we get started on the main subject at around the 24 minute mark). Afterwards, tune in (1 hr 18 min mark) for listing of local events.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><a href="http://fortworth148.libsyn.com/004-ever-to-walk-and-act-as-such"><em>Ever to Walk and Act as Such - What&#8217;s it mean to act like a Mason, anyway?</em></a></p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://texanmason.com/2017/03/09/Fourth-Podcast-Episode.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://texanmason.com/2017/03/09/Fourth-Podcast-Episode.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Freemason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Free]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Masonry]]></category><category><![CDATA[Craft]]></category><category><![CDATA[Blue]]></category><category><![CDATA[Lodge]]></category><category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category><category><![CDATA[Fort]]></category><category><![CDATA[Worth]]></category><category><![CDATA[148]]></category><pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Third Podcast Episode]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>Third podcast episode is up! Super late on the draw on actually updating my site. It&#8217;s been kind of hectic - recent change of employment.</p>
</div>
<div class="quoteblock">
<blockquote>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Brothers Rhit Moore, Grant Gates, and Gabriel Jagush get to talking about what it means to provide value to a lodge. Are you getting your money&#8217;s worth? Can you improve your lodge? What are you doing right? What about your wife? We also get sidetracked on the dreaded subject of dues for a bit.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>We continue with more information on the Italian Affair, discuss a recent arson attack on our Brothers in Canada, a masonic children&#8217;s home saved from closure, and the renovation of the Colored Masonic Building in Birmingham, AL. At the end of the episode, we talk about what&#8217;s going on in the 64th district of Texas.</p>
</div>
</blockquote>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><a href="http://fortworth148.libsyn.com/episode-003-building-value"><em>Building Value - Let&#8217;s make it worth your time</em></a>.</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://texanmason.com/2017/03/06/Third-Podcast-Episode.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://texanmason.com/2017/03/06/Third-Podcast-Episode.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Freemason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Free]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Masonry]]></category><category><![CDATA[Craft]]></category><category><![CDATA[Blue]]></category><category><![CDATA[Lodge]]></category><category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category><category><![CDATA[Fort]]></category><category><![CDATA[Worth]]></category><category><![CDATA[148]]></category><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Second Podcast Episode]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>Second episode is up! It&#8217;s a triple-threat this week at the Fort Worth 148 Podcast as Brothers Rhit Moore, Grant Gates, and Gabriel Jagush talk about guarding the West Gate. It&#8217;s not fun to say, but masonry isn&#8217;t for everyone. How do you best get to know the man you want to call brother? Is he the right fit for Freemasonry, and is Freemasonry the right fit for him? How do you investigate him? These are all questions we explore in this episode. We also briefly touch on the issues our Italian brothers are experiencing, and the Florida/Cuba Grand Lodge drama. At the end of the episode, we have an update on events in and around us, so if you&#8217;re short on time, but want to know what&#8217;s going on in the 64th district, please check out the last few minutes of the podcast and we&#8217;ll get you updated.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><a href="http://www.stitcher.com/s?eid=49226934"><em>Guarding the West Gate</em></a></p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://texanmason.com/2017/02/23/Second-Podcast-Episode.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://texanmason.com/2017/02/23/Second-Podcast-Episode.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Freemason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Free]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Masonry]]></category><category><![CDATA[Craft]]></category><category><![CDATA[Blue]]></category><category><![CDATA[Lodge]]></category><category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category><category><![CDATA[Fort]]></category><category><![CDATA[Worth]]></category><category><![CDATA[148]]></category><pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Quest for Judas Maccabeus]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>Founder of the Order of Judas Maccabeus, Brother Herman Sarachan:</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://texanmason.com/images/20170220-img1.jpg" alt="Herman Sarachan">
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>My latest obsession is one that I&#8217;ve touched on before in <a href="/posts/20170112.html">the article I shared</a> by R∴W∴ Raymond Beardsley. For those of you that have not yet heard of the Order of Judas Maccabeus, it was an order founded in New York State by a group of brothers seeking a non-Christian alternative to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Knights_Templar_(Freemasonry)">Commandery</a>. The founding of the Order did involve Masons from many aspects of the Craft, including representatives and leaders from the NYS grand bodies of Chapter, Council, and Commandery.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>One of my goals has been to reach out to brothers that were involved in the Order. This has proved to be very difficult. Many of the men involved in OoJM have passed away, or don&#8217;t have an online presence, which makes reaching out a lot more difficult! When I first read the article by Brother Beardsley, I figured that I should try and see if I could contact him. That is when I found out that he had passed away about two weeks before I had found the article. No luck there, unfortunately, and may Brother Beardsley rest easy in the arms of the Creator.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Initially, I thought I had reached a dead end. However, having read the article, I had a jumping-off point: the home Chapter and home Council of the OoJM founder, Brother Herman Sarachan. I sent out emails to the recorder of Doric Council #19 and to the recorder of Hiram Chapter #62. My email to Hiram Chapter was a little bit of a Hail Mary, because I wasn&#8217;t sure if this was a reformation of Hamilton Chapter, or if it was a different entity entirely. As of yet, I still have to hear back from their recorder, so my assumption is that it is a different Chapter entirely.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>However, I was able to hear back from Brother John Dudley, the Recorder of Doric Council (also the Secretary of Northfield Lodge #426). He informed me that he had been a member of the Order and had watched it slowly die. At the time of his joining, he was the 71st member of the Genesee Valley Assemblage #1, which is is shown on the scan of his last dues card for the Order, which he sent to me:</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://texanmason.com/images/20170220-img2.jpg" alt="20170220 img2.jpg">
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Brother Dudley then put me in contact with (R∴W∴) Brother John Gallant, who was not a member of the Order, but had been in contact with Brother Beardsley. I emailed Brother Gallant to talk to him and see what I could learn, and ended up with an incredible surprise. Not only did Brother Gallant inform me that there was an Assemblage operating in Texas, he sent me a copy of the Texas ritual! I don&#8217;t feel comfortable posting/sharing the ritual in such an accessible format, so I will try to describe the document. The "Standard Work" was written by Brother Sarachan in 1974 in New York State, and the Texas ritual&#8217;s latest revision, according to the document, was in August 2007, by the late Brother Cliff Cameron. Brother Cameron was a Knight of the York Cross of Honor, and the 2007 Grand Historian of the <a href="http://www.yorkritetexas.org/council/">Grand Council of Royal and Select Masters of Texas</a>.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The Order conferred two degrees, the <em>Order of David</em> and the <em>Order of Judas Maccabeus</em>. There would have been a third order, the <em>Order of the Temple</em>, but Brother Sarachan died before he could finish it. From what I have been told, my understanding is that there were/are some efforts to finish the Order of the Temple, but I cannot verify this.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The Order of David teaches the lessons of love and devotion through the story of Jonathan and David planning David&#8217;s escape from King Saul&#8217;s grasp. The degree opens the Volume of Sacred Law (VSL) to <em>Samuel 1 18:1</em>. The officers of the Order of David are:</p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Sovereign Master</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Companion Senior Warden</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Companion Junior Warden</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Companion Captain of the Guard</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Companion Marshall</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Companion Warder</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Companion Sentinel</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>After the candidate is made a Companion of the Order of David and has observed the drama, the new Companion retires without the Assemblage&#8217;s room, and the Assemblage resumes labor in the Order of Judas Maccabeus, due to having called down to the Order of David for the purpose of conferral, and the Companion is made a Valiant Prince. The Order of Judas Maccabeus teaches the lessons of fidelity and devotion (to faith) through the story of the Maccabean revolt against the Hellenistic regime of Antiochus IV. The degree opens the VSL to either <em>Psalm 23</em> or <em>Ecclesiastes 12</em>. The officers of the Order of Judas Maccabeus are:</p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Sovereign Prince Commander</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Valiant Prince Chancellor</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Valiant Prince Orator</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Valiant Prince Cohen</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Valiant Prince Treasurer</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Valiant Prince Recorder</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Valiant Prince Captain of the Guard</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Valiant Prince Marshall</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Valiant Prince Warder</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Valiant Prince Sentinel</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>They are seated in the Assemblage room as such:</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://texanmason.com/images/20170220-img3.jpg" alt="20170220 img3.jpg">
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>There, dear readers, is where I had to go from. My next step was to find out how to contact Brother Cameron, so I reached out to the Grand Recorder of the Grand Council of Texas. I was informed that he had passed away, but that there was a Grand Chapter/Council History and Preservation Committee. I have yet to hear back from either of the emails that I sent to the committee members, unfortunately. I also reached out to the Grand College of Rites, as I am a member ("Fellow"). No dice there, either. Radio silence.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>At this point, I think I stalled out for a two weeks, because I was pretty stumped about what to do next. I talked about it with my brothers in lodge, and online, on Reddit, etc, etc, etc. It was then that someone suggested that I email Brother Arturo de Hoyos, who is an expert historian on most anything and everything Masonic. Brother de Hoyos was very friendly and informed me that this was actually an avenue of investigation that one of his associates was pursuing! The running theory is that the group is totally defunct. If so, the rituals will be printed as <a href="http://grandcollegeofrites.org/collectanea/">Collectanea</a> for the Grand College of Rites. I emailed him what I had in terms of general materials, contact information, and so forth. Hopefully something will turn up soon!</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In the meanwhile, I am continuing my search. I&#8217;m not sure where this will lead me. Honestly, I am really hoping that there&#8217;s still an active Assemblage somewhere in Texas. All you would need is to to grab five companions of the Royal Arch, and then have them inducted into the Order. That being the required number of Valiant Princes for an Assemblage to form and meet, perhaps there is hope for the future of Judas Maccabeus?</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://texanmason.com/2017/02/20/A-New-Obsession.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://texanmason.com/2017/02/20/A-New-Obsession.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Freemason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Free]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Masonry]]></category><category><![CDATA[Craft]]></category><category><![CDATA[Blue]]></category><category><![CDATA[Lodge]]></category><category><![CDATA[York]]></category><category><![CDATA[Rite]]></category><category><![CDATA[Jewish]]></category><category><![CDATA[Knights]]></category><category><![CDATA[Knight]]></category><category><![CDATA[Templar]]></category><category><![CDATA[Alternative]]></category><category><![CDATA[Judas]]></category><category><![CDATA[Maccabeus]]></category><category><![CDATA[Judah]]></category><category><![CDATA[Maccabee]]></category><pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[First Podcast Episode]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>Well then, here we go. Jumping into the deep end with my lodge brother, Rhit Moore. We have decided to revive the Fort Worth 148 Podcast. Let&#8217;s see how this goes! Our goal is to do good work, spread news for the Craft, and get nerdy as hell real quick. Check out our first episode, <a href="http://www.stitcher.com/podcast/fort-worth-148""><em>Tech and the Lodge</em></a>.</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://texanmason.com/2017/02/17/First-Podcast-Episode.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://texanmason.com/2017/02/17/First-Podcast-Episode.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Freemason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Free]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Masonry]]></category><category><![CDATA[Craft]]></category><category><![CDATA[Blue]]></category><category><![CDATA[Lodge]]></category><category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category><category><![CDATA[Fort]]></category><category><![CDATA[Worth]]></category><category><![CDATA[148]]></category><pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Traveling Gavel]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>The Grand Lodge of Texas (AF&amp;AM) 64th District Traveling Gavel:</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://texanmason.com/images/20170209-img1.jpg" alt="20170209 img1.jpg">
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Tonight we had the privilege of visiting Handley Lodge. It was a pretty great experience! They had, up to this point, been the holders of the GLoTX 64th District Traveling Gavel. This was a program that was originally started by my lodge (148). In order to capture the gavel, your lodge has to show up with 7 or more brothers. The visit can be either during a stated meeting, or a called meeting. If  multiple lodge attempt a capture, whichever lodge has the most lodges present takes it home, with a coin toss being the  method used to break ties.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The brothers from Handley welcomed us with open arms and we had an absolutely great time. This was a very well-attended stated meeting! Even Arlington Lodge (438, I think) sent a contingent of brothers in their own attempt to make a capture. At one point, someone from Sweet Home Lodge tried to see if there were enough plural members of Sweet Home Lodoge for them to take it! That would have been a very difficult retrieval as they only open lodge in the Master&#8217;s Degree, and as such, would require us to send only our Master Masons.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The food was great - the OES chapter at Handley really knows how to knock it out of the park.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Here we are with the Worshipful Master of Handley Lodge, Haskell Rogers (III):</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://texanmason.com/images/20170209-img2.jpg" alt="20170209 img2.jpg">
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Bonus picture of our group in front of the very-appropriate "COME AND TAKE IT" flag:</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://texanmason.com/images/20170209-img3.jpg" alt="20170209 img3.jpg">
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>For more information on the Traveling Gavel, check out the <a href="http://www.64th.org/traveling-gavel-rules/">64th district&#8217;s page on it</a>. I sincerely urge anyone in the 64th district to "COME AND TAKE IT," so to speak, as we will try our damndest to take it right back.</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://texanmason.com/2017/02/09/Competitive-Brotherhood.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://texanmason.com/2017/02/09/Competitive-Brotherhood.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Freemason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Free]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Masonry]]></category><category><![CDATA[Craft]]></category><category><![CDATA[Blue]]></category><category><![CDATA[Lodge]]></category><pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA["The Order of Judas Maccabeus" by R∴W∴ Raymond Beardsly]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div id="preamble">
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I was trying to find out some more info about this Order when it came up a couple of days ago. Found a PDF called "The Pyramid Texts" and figured it would be useful to have this in a more web-friendly format.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>If you want to read more articles like this, I think that the Philalethes Society actually offers an optional CD with a massive back catalogue of articles.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_the_order_of_judas_maccabeus">THE ORDER OF JUDAS MACCABEUS</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p><strong>Raymond R. Beardsley</strong></p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><strong>The Philalethes - October 1991</strong></p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In the mid-1970&#8217;s, a group of York Rite Masons met in the Rochester area of upstate New York to consider the initiation of a new organization with the purpose of eventually proposing it as a new Body to be incorporated in the York Rite of Freemasonry. The inception of this idea had emanated from the fertile brain of the late Brother Herman Sarachan, often referred to as Mr. Mason in the Rochester area. Brother Sarachan had a distinguished Masonic record, having actively participated in both the Scottish and York Rites, as well as having served as a District Deputy Grand Master in the Monroe County area. He had been the High Priest of Hamilton Chapter #62 and the Illustrious Master of Doric Council #19.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>For many years, Brother Sarachan edited a column in the Monroe Masonic News (the monthly Masonic publication in the Rochester area) entitled: "Dear Brother Herman," in which he answered questions regarding Masonry - history, biography, definition, procedure, law, ritual, protocol, etc. His articles were later incorporated into a book under the same title, published in 1979; in addition, Brother Sarachan had previously published a book on the history of Freemasonry in the Rochester and Monroe County area of New York.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Brother Sarachan believed that there was a need for an additional body in the York Rite for those Masons who either could not for religious reasons or would not for personal reasons join the Commandery of Knights Templar. The first two York Rite Bodies, the Royal Arch Chapter and the Council of Cryptic Masons, like the Symbolic Lodge, are non-sectarian; however, the Commandery of Knights Templar is distinctly a Christian Order of Masonry and is also a military-type organization with uniforms, drills and inspections. As a result, Members of the Chapter and Council who are not Christians or who do not favor the militaristic atmosphere of the Commandery do not have a comparable body to join, which would be more suitable to their religious or personal beliefs and mores. With this in mind, Brother Sarachan proposed that a new body be initiated to meet the needs and desires of these particular Masonic Brethren but which would welcome all Masons who wished to participate. The organization would be known as The Order of Judas Maccabeus.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Judas Maccabeus was the renowned leader of the Jews when they revolted against Roman hegemony in the second century, B.C., particularly after the Romans had desecrated the Temple at Jerusalem by erecting a statue of Zeus over the altar. Under the leadership of Judas Maccabeus, the Jews regained control of Jerusalem and the Temple for a period of time celebrated in Jewish history. Because of his prestige and stature in Hebrew history and tradition, the name of Judas Maccabeus was considered most appropriate for the new body. The Order of Judas Maccabeus would be founded on a non-sectarian basis and without military accouterments, with the goal that it would eventually become a parallel Body to the Commandery.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Thus, in 1974, a group of some 30 York Rite leaders in the local area met in the Rochester Temple to formally consider The Order of Judas Maccabeus. Present were Masons prominent in all the York Rite Bodies, including past heads of all of the Grand Bodies in the State of New York: M∴ E∴ Frank Allen of the Grand Chapter, M∴ I∴ Bruce Dayton of the Grand Council and R∴ E∴ Ward Ekas of the Grand Commandery. All in attendance were unanimously in agreement as to the desirability of instituting a complementary Body to the Commandery that would more appropriately meet the needs of our Jewish and other non-Christian or non-military-minded Companions. It should be born in mind that the majority of York Rite Masons present were Christians and members of the local Commanderies.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The Order of Judas Maccabeus was originally to encompass three Orders: The Order of David, The Order of Judas Maccabeus and The Order of the Temple (referring to the Jewish Temple). The Order of David teaches the lesson of unselfish love and devotion and uses as its framework the story of David and Jonathan, as depicted in the Old Testament in the Book of First Samuel. The Order of Judas Maccabeus teaches the lesson of fidelity and devotion to faith and uses as its framework the revolt of the Jews in 168 B.C. against the Roman hierarchy of Antiochus, who had prohibited the practice of the Jewish faith and had desecrated the Temple, as related in the Apocryphal Books of the Maccabeus.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>These first two Orders were prepared under the aegis of Brother Sarachan, and, to date, have formed the basis for initiation into the Order. The Order of the Temple, which ultimately is to form the final phase of initiation into the Order, has not been completed. Brother Sarachan&#8217;s health failed and he passed on before he could turn his attention to the proposed Order of the Temple. However, it is now in the process of formulation, and much thought is going into its preparation, in order that it may take its place on a level with such awe-inspiring exemplifications as the Royal Arch Degree of the Chapter, the Super Excellent Degree of the Council and the Order of the Temple of the Commandery.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Members of The Order of Judas Maccabeus are titled "Valiant Princes" and constituent Bodies are termed "Assemblages," whose principal officers are Commander, Chancellor, Orator, Treasurer, Recorder, Captain of the Guard, Lecturer, Marshall, Warden and Sentinel. The premier Assemblage, inaugurated in the Rochester area, is known as Genesee Valley Assemblage #1.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>A number of other Assemblages have been instituted in New York State, specifically in New York, Long Island and Buffalo. Also, Assemblages have been inaugurated in the States of Connecticut and New Jersey. Numerous inquiries have been received from interested York Rite Masons from such States as Ohio, Michigan, Wisconsin, Arizona and California, to name a few.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Although the early years of Genesee Valley Assemblage #1 did not always run smoothly and for awhile the original enthusiasm was somewhat abated, it is now prospering with a large number of new members. Whereas the charter membership was largely Christian, in recent years a number of our Jewish and other non-Christian Brethren have joined. In the meantime, with the emergence of other Assemblages about New York and adjoining States, a Grand Assemblage was instituted a few years ago with the presiding officer designated to be "The Most Sovereign Grand Commander of North America."</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Any inquiries and questions should be forwarded to the above address. Although there may be those who question the desirability of a new Masonic organization, the criterion that should be applied is the need for and function of such a new Masonic entity. Over the past 35 years, we have experienced the inception of two new Masonic organizations which met specific needs and desires and, as a result, have been highly successful. These are The York Rite Sovereign College of North America and The National Camping Travelers. The first originated for Masons active in all four York Rite Bodies, and the second for Masons and their families interested in camping. Both of these Masonic organization have, in a relatively few years, grown tremendously with both of them having well over 100 constituent Bodies throughout the United States and Canada.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In like manner, The Order of Judas Maccabeus was founded to meet a distinct need in York Rite Masonry. Because of this, those of us who have been intimately connected with its formulation and establishment feel that it will play a unique and increasingly important role in The York Rite of Freemasonry.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><strong><em>Raymond R. Beardsley (December 8, 1925 - December 28, 2016)</em></strong> <em>was a member and Past Master of Northfield Lodge #426 F. &amp; A.M. in Pittsford, NY. He was the Past Most Illustrious Grand Master of the Grand Council of the State of New York, Past District Deputy Grand High Priest, Past Commander of Cyrene-Monroe Commandery #12, and Past District Deputy Grand Master 2nd Monroe District. He was a Scottish Rite Mason and a member of Damascus Shrine in Webster, NY.</em></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>http://texanmason.com/2017/01/12/Swords-and-Jesus-no-Swords-and-Jews-yes.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://texanmason.com/2017/01/12/Swords-and-Jesus-no-Swords-and-Jews-yes.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Freemason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Free]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Masonry]]></category><category><![CDATA[Craft]]></category><category><![CDATA[Blue]]></category><category><![CDATA[Lodge]]></category><category><![CDATA[York]]></category><category><![CDATA[Rite]]></category><category><![CDATA[Jewish]]></category><category><![CDATA[Knights]]></category><category><![CDATA[Knight]]></category><category><![CDATA[Templar]]></category><category><![CDATA[Alternative]]></category><category><![CDATA[Judas]]></category><category><![CDATA[Maccabeus]]></category><category><![CDATA[Judah]]></category><category><![CDATA[Maccabee]]></category><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Rant on Degree Work]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>If you volunteer for a part in a degree, you should actually know that part and be able to deliver it.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>We had an FC degree today for an EA who has been waiting quite a while. Very happy for him since he has been putting a lot of effort into the work. I had been reading up on the JW position in case we needed to fill in chairs since I had heard we were going to be a lighter crowd that usual - I usually play the part of the JD because I like to play with light switches.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I was initially slated to be the JW pro-tem, but was shortly told that I would be JD, as one of our older brothers from out of state had asked to contribute to the degree. Not a big deal, since he&#8217;s older and doesn&#8217;t get to do much, so I stepped aside, but in the interest of full disclosure, I really actually was pretty excited to sit in the South for this degree, and was kind of bummed out. However, <a href="https://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=Genesis+1%3A1-3&amp;version=KJV">I do like light switches&#8230;&#8203;</a></p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Anyway, this fellow was raised in a different state (now has our lodge as a "home base" of sorts), and is even a PM, but different states are different states, so he was asked if he knew the lines for Texas' ritual. He said "no," so I played SD to his JW while one of our older members, Centenarian Brother (turning 100 in a few months!) fed him lines. We did this a couple of times, and the delivery was&#8230;&#8203; shaky at best. He is older, has memory issues, and his speech is very difficult to decipher. However, he was really wanting to do the part, so we went ahead.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Right before the degree, our SW pro-tem leaned over to me and expressed his concerns about the South. Another red flag, I suppose. The degree happens, and sure enough, he forgot every line, had to be prompted more than once per line on multiple occasions, and forgot to display the DG &amp; PS after the obligation while the WM and SW next to him were displaying them. There was a quiet groan from our SW at one point.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>While the candidate was back in the prep room, I went over the lines with him, again playing the part of SD while Centenarian Brother taught him his lines. Again, same deal. The same thing happened during closing. It was incredibly frustrating to watch.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>After the lodge closed and the acting JW had left, the SW went on a short, quiet rant to a few people that ended with "this was a disaster."</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I am salty? A little bit. I don&#8217;t if it&#8217;s without merit, though.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>So please, folks, if you know your lines, by all means, please, help out. If you don&#8217;t, please come to floor school, or observe degrees, or both. I love floor school. I love degrees. I would go and do every day if I had the time.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>TL;DR: I&#8217;m whinging on the internet, I suppose. Please forgive me.</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://texanmason.com/2016/11/29/Gabe-loses-his-Compasses-for-a-bit.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://texanmason.com/2016/11/29/Gabe-loses-his-Compasses-for-a-bit.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Freemason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Free]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Masonry]]></category><category><![CDATA[Craft]]></category><category><![CDATA[Blue]]></category><category><![CDATA[Lodge]]></category><category><![CDATA[Ritual]]></category><category><![CDATA[Memory]]></category><category><![CDATA[Acting]]></category><category><![CDATA[Performance]]></category><category><![CDATA[Knowledge]]></category><pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Bad Linguistics]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div id="preamble">
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p><em>This was originally posted to a private lodge Facebook group for Fort Worth Lodge #148.</em></p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Recently, I tried to translate "Mind and Conscience" into both Latin and Hebrew. The Latin translation was very easy: <strong>mens et conscientia.</strong> Hey, you can see how similar it is, right? When it came to Hebrew, I didn&#8217;t get to "conscience" for a long time because of the rabbit hole that "mind" lead down. The Hebrew word for "conscience," by the way, is מַצְפּוּן or <strong>matspon</strong>, which means "conscience" or "scruple," and anciently meant "hidden treasure." That&#8217;s a discussion for another time, I think.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>So, anyway, what <em>does</em> the word "mind" look like in Hebrew?</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Well, that&#8217;s not a simple question with a simple answer. Both in contemporary Hebrew and the Hebrew of the Tanakh / Old Testament, there are many words which are translated to English and the Romance languages as "mind," but do not actually have the <strong>meaning</strong> of "mind." You see, the word "mind," as we understand it in English, is uniquely colored by the fact that it is a Romance language word.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In Spanish (and Portuguese &amp; Italian) we say "mente," in Romanian, it&#8217;s "minte," and so forth. However, this isn&#8217;t shared into other language families, or regions, or even into other Romance languages! In French (Romance language family), for example, the word is "espirit" from the Latin "spiritus" ("breath," "breeze," or "ghost"). In German (different language family, same region) it&#8217;s "Geist" which means "spirit" first, then "ghost," then "mind."</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Then we get to the Semitic language family. Whole different ballgame, folks. As far as I can tell, there is no one word in Hebrew that, strictly speaking, <strong>actually</strong> means "mind" as we understand it, only words that can be acceptably substituted. I have compiled a small list of them, and what I&#8217;ve learned about them. Some of these words were used anciently in the Tanakh / Old Testament, and some of these are more contemporary. My apologies to any of our brethren who may take offense to the writing of the Tetragrammaton; I hope I have done this respectfully in an academic context.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_heart">Heart - לבב</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The word לב or <strong>leb</strong> (also לבב or <strong>lebab</strong>) refers to the literal organ of the heart, with secondary, figurative meaning as the seat of emotions and appetites, specifically that of Courage. It can also mean "inner person" or "[the] will."</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_spirit">Spirit - רוח</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Another possible translation is רוח or <strong>ruach</strong>. It primarily means "wind," but it can also mean "breath." It has a tertiary meaning of "spirit" (but still not "mind").</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>It also has a prophetic form, רוח הקודש (<strong>ruach</strong> <strong>hakodesh</strong>), which is the name of the Holy Spirit in the Tanakh. There are other forms &amp; words of which <strong>ruach</strong> is a component. רוח אלוהים (<strong>ruach</strong> <strong>Elohim</strong>) and רוח-אל (<strong>ruach-El</strong>) also refer to the Spirit of God. רוח יהוה (<strong>ruach</strong> <strong>Adonai</strong>) means "The Spirit of the Lord" and רוח אדני יהוה (<strong>ruach</strong> <strong>Adonai</strong> <strong>Adonai</strong>) means "The Spirit of the Lord God," which are both commonly and improperly translated as "The Sprit of Jehovah" and "The Spirit of the Lord Jehovah," respectively. The YHWH discussion is a whole different rabbit-hole.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_soul">Soul - נפש</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The spirit of a person or an animal is נפש or <strong>nepesh</strong>, which is directly translated as "soul." It can also mean "life," refer to a person / human being, or will/intent. It also has an antiquated meaning of "breath," which reminds us of רוח / ruah. It can be used to define life and consciousness as we understand it in humans and animals of higher intelligence, which is a very close approximation (but not exact) of "mind."</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_marrow">Marrow - מֹחַ</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>More commonly spelled מוֹחַ, but anciently מֹחַ or <strong>moach</strong>, this word is biblically used to refer to bone marrow (and still is in some contexts), and more recently, primarily in reference to the brain. It closely relates to <strong>ruach</strong>, "spirit."</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_consciousness">Consciousness - תודעה</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>A closer word still is תודעה or <strong>toda&#8217;a</strong>, which can refer to an awareness or a consciousness. This is one of the most commonly used words to substitute for mind, but still isn&#8217;t a catch-all. The "mind-body problem," for example, is the "guf-<strong>nepesh</strong> problem," while something like "a state of mind" is translated as "a state of <strong>toda&#8217;a</strong>."</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_reason">Reason - תבונה</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The word תבונה or <strong>tevunah</strong> primarily stands for "reason." It can also stand for a wisdom, or intelligence. The word for "understanding" is derived from <strong>tevunah</strong>. The words for prudence, discreetness, knowledge, etc, are also derivations of this word. In <em>Mishlei</em>/Proverbs 3:19-20, we read:</p>
</div>
<div class="quoteblock">
<blockquote>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>"<em>Hashem</em> / God laid the earth&#8217;s foundations with wisdom (<strong>chochmah</strong>), by understanding (<strong>tevunah</strong>) he set the heavens in place; through His knowledge (<strong>daat</strong>) the depths were cleaved, and the clouds let drop the dew."&lt;/i&gt;</p>
</div>
</blockquote>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In this case, Rabbeinu Yonah explains that <strong>chochmah</strong> is the lowest form of learning - the information that is conveyed to you from someone else. <strong>tevunah</strong> is the information or understanding that one arrives to after meditating upon the <strong>chochmah</strong> one has been taught.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_intelligence">Intelligence - שכל</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Shared in Hebrew and Yiddish with slightly different meanings, שכל or <strong>sechel</strong> means intelligence, brains, wisdom, or in wisdom. Recently, it has also come to refer to common sense and "smarts." However, it doesn&#8217;t just quite translate to any of those, just like "mind" doesn&#8217;t translate to it or the other previously-discussed words. In older Hebrew usage, the word had very serious moral and ethical connotations that it does not really have today. In contemporary Yiddish, the word denotes a very respected quality regarding one&#8217;s pursuit of knowledge and ability to leave the world a better place.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>As you can see, there&#8217;s no one word that means exactly what we conceive of as "mind." This is not uncommon, as many languages have words that don&#8217;t quite translate well, like the Portuguese "saudade," the Spanish "sobremesa," the German "Weltschmerz," etc. The closest word, in my opinion, appears to be תודעה (<strong>toda&#8217;a</strong>), which is most commonly used in contemporary Hebrew. Other words I found to be close in the semitic language family are שכל (<strong>sechel</strong>, Yiddish for "understanding," shared with Hebrew but with a slightly different meaning), and عقل (<strong>eaql</strong>, Arabic for "reason").</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_online_resources">Online resources:</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/%D7%9C%D7%91" class="bare">https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/%D7%9C%D7%91</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/%D7%A8%D7%95%D7%97" class="bare">https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/%D7%A8%D7%95%D7%97</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/%D7%A0%D7%A4%D7%A9" class="bare">https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/%D7%A0%D7%A4%D7%A9</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://torah.org/torah-portion/hamaayan-5769-bereishis/" class="bare">https://torah.org/torah-portion/hamaayan-5769-bereishis/</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/%D7%A9%D7%9B%D7%9C" class="bare">https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/%D7%A9%D7%9B%D7%9C</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://www.momentmag.com/jewish-word-sechel/" class="bare">http://www.momentmag.com/jewish-word-sechel/</a></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>http://texanmason.com/2016/10/26/Gabe-engages-in-shoddy-academics.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://texanmason.com/2016/10/26/Gabe-engages-in-shoddy-academics.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Freemason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Free]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Masonry]]></category><category><![CDATA[Craft]]></category><category><![CDATA[Blue]]></category><category><![CDATA[Lodge]]></category><category><![CDATA[Hebrew]]></category><category><![CDATA[Latin]]></category><category><![CDATA[Translate]]></category><category><![CDATA[Translation]]></category><pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA["...but he needs knowledge of the TRUE secrets of Freemasonry."]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>I attended a function recently as the guest of one of my Brothers, along with a MM from one of my sister lodges. Was not able to attend the meeting itself, obviously, but was allowed to join in for a hearty dinner and listen to a pretty good talk on the book of Ecclesiastes. Fascinating stuff. Shook a lot of hands, met a lot of new people.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Anyway, I had two exchanges, one short and one long/frustrating, with Brothers I already know. The short one feels like it played into the longer one.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>After the dinner, I talked to a Brother I knew, commenting on how well we had been received. "Oh, absolutely, I had no doubt that you&#8217;d love it. [NSAB] is the best, friendliest body in all the Fraternity. You just can&#8217;t compare." I brushed this one off because we had very definitely been greeted with open arms. I didn&#8217;t even think about this until I was meditating on the other exchange.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The other exchange was with a Brother who I know even better. He&#8217;s a very influential brother in our Temple. We&#8217;d been talking about different opportunities in the appendant bodies after my raising. He&#8217;s very keen on seeing people join [NSAB], which is great, and I plan to join it eventually, but I also want to take some time and "soak" in Blue Lodge. We talked about our line officers and I mentioned how outstanding I think our JW has been.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>This is when things started to get more frustrating. This line got busted out (paraphrased from memory): "Well, he&#8217;s a very innate leader, and I&#8217;m very proud of him, but he doesn&#8217;t know the <em>true</em> secrets of Freemasonry. If he&#8217;s going to be an effective leader, he needs to ask more questions about what happened in his Master&#8217;s Degree, and have them answered, and he can only do that in [NSAB]. That&#8217;s where he&#8217;ll gain leadership skills, too. Ninety percent of what you hear in the Blue Lodge is bullshit unless you follow up on it elsewhere. We have the answers. You can&#8217;t be a good Officer without having learned from [NSAB], and when you sit in the chairs, I want you have done that first. You&#8217;ll gain a lot of leadership skills that you need if you do that before getting in the chairs." This is a sentiment I have heard before from a lot of older Brothers in [NSAB].</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I was pretty frustrated by that. Right now, none of our line officers have been through any of the appendant bodies, including some that have been in Lodge for a while now, and the vast majority of them have been doing an incredible job. We have some BLO guys, but we also have some that are considering joining up with the appendant bodies when it&#8217;s the right time. I feel like it&#8217;s very dismissive from my Brothers in the appendant bodies to place so much emphasis on things outside of Blue Lodge in specific relation to the running of the Blue Lodge.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I&#8217;m neither really hear nor there on the appendant bodies, because I&#8217;m really interested, but I want to wait for a while, and I have no plans or machinations set on getting into the Chairs because it is <em>waaaaaaay</em> too early for me to have that kind of discussion. I just feel like this a really common sort of sentiment among guys in appendant bodies, and that it&#8217;s incredibly dismissive/disrespectful of Craft Lodge in general.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Am I out of line in feeling a little miffed about this? I don&#8217;t know for sure, but I am.</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://texanmason.com/2016/10/21/Today-in-My-Brothers-in-Non-Specified-Appendant-Body-are-Driving-Me-Up-the-Wall.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://texanmason.com/2016/10/21/Today-in-My-Brothers-in-Non-Specified-Appendant-Body-are-Driving-Me-Up-the-Wall.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Freemason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Free]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Masonry]]></category><category><![CDATA[Craft]]></category><category><![CDATA[Blue]]></category><category><![CDATA[Lodge]]></category><category><![CDATA[Scottish]]></category><category><![CDATA[York]]></category><category><![CDATA[Rite]]></category><category><![CDATA[Shrine]]></category><category><![CDATA[Appendant]]></category><category><![CDATA[Body]]></category><category><![CDATA[Bodies]]></category><pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Prep Room]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p><em>This was originally posted to a private lodge Facebook group for Fort Worth Lodge #148.</em></p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><strong>These are some notes on a reddit comment by <a href="http://www.arslatomorum.com/vitae-maconarium/">V∴I∴ Brother Jason Mitchell</a>, on the subject of how the Room of Preparation should be set up. All I&#8217;ve done is format it for ease of reading.</strong></p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The Prep Room is ritual space. It is not a closet. It is not storage. It is not a utility room. It is just as "sacred" as the Lodge room proper, the altar, and the VSL itself. Clean out your prep room, and make it "sacred" ritual space.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The Prep Room experience is part of the ritual. It should be one candidate at a time (never exceed one candidate). It is not a locker room. The Candidate should feel midly unwelcome, and the Officers present need to be coldly professional and oppressively silent. There are no smiles in the prep room. There is no joviality in the prep room. Before the Candidate knocks on the door, he needs at least one heartbeat of hesitation and fear. He needs to look at the exit and make the choice to stay.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The prep room should be dark or dimly light. One light bulbs roughly 20W with a color temperature 2700-3000K (or LED or florescent equivalent) is enough. Bright bulbs, white bulbs, or colors are to be avoided. Candles are another matter, but most temples won&#8217;t cover the insurance for open flame.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Paint the town red. The prep room walls should be neither white nor black, but a neutral earth tone. With the proper illumination, the proper effect is achieved. Black and white walls ruin the effect. Neutral colors. Always use neutral colors in ritual environments. They just work better with illumination and colors, especially in low-light conditions.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Symbols. Only ever include symbols directly reference in your Grand Lodge&#8217;s Work, lectures, or monitors. The idea is to foreshadow things to come.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Know your work. It should go without saying that the prep room is the first ritual experience of the candidate. If you have to read the Work, you&#8217;ve already lost him.</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://texanmason.com/2016/10/05/Maybe-not-quite-the-Chamber-of-Reflection.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://texanmason.com/2016/10/05/Maybe-not-quite-the-Chamber-of-Reflection.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Freemason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Free]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Masonry]]></category><category><![CDATA[Craft]]></category><category><![CDATA[Blue]]></category><category><![CDATA[Lodge]]></category><category><![CDATA[Jason Mitchell]]></category><category><![CDATA[Prep]]></category><category><![CDATA[Room]]></category><category><![CDATA[Chamber]]></category><category><![CDATA[Reflection]]></category><pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Osirian Musings]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p><em>This was originally posted to a private lodge Facebook group for Fort Worth Lodge #148.</em></p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In the laundromat, I sat down to read a book that Rhit lent me (The Initiatic Experience) and while reading, I had an externally quiet, internally loud "A-HA!" moment.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In the second chapter (which is as far as I&#8217;ve gotten so far), there&#8217;s a lot of talk about the basics of the Egyptian death/afterlife mythos, including the resurrection/rebirth of Osiris, who was buried far in the West. After reading this, something kind of clicked for me and I tried to remember what I learned about Egypt in school!</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>According to the ancient Egyptians, the West was representative of Death. So much so, in fact, that people would traditionally build homes and regular temples on the East side of the Nile (the land of the living, where the Sun rose) instead of on the West side where tombs and funerary temples were built (the land of the dead, where the Sun set).</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In the Lodge, or at least in Texan Lodges (as well as many others, I&#8217;m sure), the door through which the candidate enters is on the western side of the room, just north of the Senior Warden&#8217;s chair. Here we see that he&#8217;s in a dark place, being on the "west bank" where the sun sets (as well as towards the North of the Lodge). By receiving the candidate, we bring him through the doors of the Lodge, from West to East.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Taking the West as Death, the direction of East as Life, and the doors as the barrier between those two worlds, not only is the candidate brought from darkness (western sunset) to light (eastern sunrise), but he is also reborn from death (west, outside the lodge room) to life (east, into the lodge room) as a new man and Mason.</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://texanmason.com/2016/09/20/Or-Reading-Too-Much-Into-Things.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://texanmason.com/2016/09/20/Or-Reading-Too-Much-Into-Things.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Freemason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Free]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Masonry]]></category><category><![CDATA[Osiris]]></category><category><![CDATA[Egypt]]></category><category><![CDATA[Death]]></category><category><![CDATA[Rebirth]]></category><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Evolution of Scottish Rite Masonry]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_complicated_flowcharts_scottish_rite_edition">Complicated flowcharts: Scottish Rite edition</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Original flowchart:</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://texanmason.com/images/20160919-img1.png" alt="Original flowchart">
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Cleaned-up version that I made:</p>
</div>
<div id="img-clean" class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<a class="image" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/gjagush/gjagush.github.io/master/images/20160919-img2.jpg"><img src="http://texanmason.com/images/20160919-img2.jpg" alt="Cleaned-Up Version"></a>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>http://texanmason.com/2016/09/19/Complicated-flowcharts-Scottish-Rite-edition.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://texanmason.com/2016/09/19/Complicated-flowcharts-Scottish-Rite-edition.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Freemason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Free]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Masonry]]></category><category><![CDATA[Craft]]></category><category><![CDATA[Blue]]></category><category><![CDATA[Lodge]]></category><category><![CDATA[Scottish Rite]]></category><category><![CDATA[Charts]]></category><category><![CDATA[Evolution]]></category><pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[About Me]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Texas Aggie - Petroleum Engineering (B.S.), 2013</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Current resident of Fort Worth, Texas</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Big on dogs</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Heavily tattooed</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Christian</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Hopeless geek</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://texanmason.com/1901/01/01/Why-I-Have-No-Free-Time-Anymore.html"><strong>Freemason</strong></a></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>]]></description><link>http://texanmason.com/1901/01/02/About-Me.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://texanmason.com/1901/01/02/About-Me.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 1901 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Vitae Maconarium]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_blue_lodge">Blue Lodge</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="__a_href_https_www_facebook_com_fortworthlodge148_fort_worth_lodge_148_a_grand_lodge_of_texas_a_f_a_m"><a href="https://www.facebook.com/fortworthlodge148/">Fort Worth Lodge #148</a> (Grand Lodge of Texas, A.F. &amp; A.M.)</h3>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>July 17, 2016 - regularly initiated as an Entered Apprentice.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>September 26, 2016 - passed to the degree of Fellowcraft.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>November 21, 2016 - raised to the sublime degree of a Master Mason.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_instruction_certifications_grand_lodge_of_texas_a_f_a_m">Instruction Certifications (Grand Lodge of Texas, A.F. &amp; A.M.)</h3>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>March 25, 2016 - passed "C"-level certification exam (trial lectures, opening and closing lodges)</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_york_rite">York Rite</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="__a_href_https_www_facebook_com_texaschapterandcouncil_texas_chapter_362_r_a_m_a"><a href="https://www.facebook.com/TexasChapterAndCouncil/">Texas Chapter #362, R.A.M.</a></h3>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>March 14, 2017 - advanced to the honorable degree of Mark Master Mason.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>March 21, 2017 - regularly seated in the Oriental Chair as a Past Master.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>March 21, 2017 - received and  acknowledged as a Most Excellent Master.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>March 27, 2017 - exalted to the most sublime Degree of the Royal Arch.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="__a_href_https_www_facebook_com_texaschapterandcouncil_texas_council_321_r_s_m_a"><a href="https://www.facebook.com/TexasChapterAndCouncil/">Texas Council #321, R. &amp; S.M.</a></h3>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>April 11, 2017 - introduced as a Royal Master</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>April 11, 2017 - chosen as a Select Master</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="__a_href_http_www_worthcommandery_org_worth_commandery_19_a"><a href="http://www.worthcommandery.org/">Worth Commandery #19</a></h3>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>April 15, 2017 - constituted a Knight of the Red Cross.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>April 15, 2017 - created a Knight of Malta.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>April 15, 2017 - dubbed and created a Knight Templar.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_research_bodies">Research Bodies</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="__a_href_http_grandcollegeofrites_org_grand_college_of_rites_a"><a href="http://grandcollegeofrites.org/">Grand College of Rites</a></h3>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>January 31, 2017 - Joined as a Fellow of the Grand College of Rites.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="__a_href_http_www_texaslodgeofresearch_org_texas_lodge_of_research_a"><a href="http://www.texaslodgeofresearch.org/">Texas Lodge of Research</a></h3>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>March 18, 2017 - Elected an Associate Member of the Texas Lodge of Research.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>http://texanmason.com/1901/01/01/Why-I-Have-No-Free-Time-Anymore.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://texanmason.com/1901/01/01/Why-I-Have-No-Free-Time-Anymore.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 1901 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>