<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Texan Mason]]></title><description><![CDATA[A Millennial in the Quarries, Yelling into the Void]]></description><link>http://texanmason.com</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2017 21:21:05 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://texanmason.com/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[Sixth Podcast Episode]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>I&#8217;m actually not sure that I posted the fifth episode of the podcast here. Not a huge deal since that&#8217;s an automatic deal! Here is the sixth episode.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>On this week&#8217;s fireside chat, Brothers Rhit Moore, Grant Gates, and Gabriel Jagush are joined by a special guest: Brother Junior Warden Will Weir of Fort Worth #148! Brother Will is the head of the 148 degree team. What are the benefits of a degree team? Who needs to get involved? How should you approach running and maintaining a team? D&#8217;ya got a fancy look? These questions and more get tackled in this episode as Will gives us some insight. Thanks for listening!</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Main discussion starts at around 11:37 and local events listing starts at 1:29:30.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><a href="http://fortworth148.libsyn.com/006-the-art-of-the-degree-team"><em>The Art of the Degree Team</em></a></p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://texanmason.com/2017/03/23/Sixth-Podcast-Episode.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://texanmason.com/2017/03/23/Sixth-Podcast-Episode.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Freemason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Free]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Masonry]]></category><category><![CDATA[Craft]]></category><category><![CDATA[Blue]]></category><category><![CDATA[Lodge]]></category><category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category><category><![CDATA[Fort]]></category><category><![CDATA[Worth]]></category><category><![CDATA[148]]></category><pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Advanced to the Mark Master Degree!]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>Today I was advanced to the degree of Mark Master Mason! I was one of three candidates. It was a fun and interesting experience. The degree team did a great job despite having a bunch of peoople missing - those filling in did very admirably. There was joviality (something very strange compared to my Blue Lodge experience) and quiet, solemn moments. Overall, it was a pretty wonderful time. Next stop: Virtual Past Master and Most Excellent Master!</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://texanmason.com/2017/03/14/MMM-delicious.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://texanmason.com/2017/03/14/MMM-delicious.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Freemason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Free]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Masonry]]></category><category><![CDATA[Craft]]></category><category><![CDATA[Royal]]></category><category><![CDATA[Arch]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mark]]></category><category><![CDATA[Master]]></category><category><![CDATA[Chapter]]></category><category><![CDATA[York]]></category><category><![CDATA[Rite]]></category><pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Handley Lodge Captures the Travel Gavel]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>Where the magic happens:</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://texanmason.com/images/20170313-temple.jpg" alt="20170313 temple.jpg">
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Last night was pretty great!</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Fort Worth Lodge had its stated meeting night, and I was pleasantly surprised to see so many visitors - at first only minorly so, then majorly so. I shared the elevator with three or four brothers from Handley Lodge on the way up to our dining hall&#8230;&#8203; Then I quickly realized, as the time went on, that they were coming out in force! Our little dining hall was packed. Handley Lodge brought out 15 brothers to come help take the travel gavel.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The Grand Lodge of Texas (AF&amp;AM) 64th District Traveling Gavel:</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://texanmason.com/images/20170209-img1.jpg" alt="20170209 img1.jpg">
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The room was abuzz with excitement. Many of the Fort Worth Members were whispering to each other over the food - cooked on the Fort Worth Lodge #148 Smoker, of course - as we were and are totally psyched to get so many visitors. I pro-tem&#8217;d the Senior Deacon&#8217;s part, and began running around the dining hall, collecting names and titles as fast as I could.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The time to file into the lodge room came, and we ran out of aprons! We had to dig in the closet for a third box of aprons. We had a total attendance of 54 brothers. Once visitors were introduced, all first time visitors were given a Fort Worth Lodge pin.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>One of my little treasures, the Fort Worth Lodge #148 pin that was given to me the night that I was raised:</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://texanmason.com/images/20170313-pin.jpg" alt="20170313 pin.jpg">
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>We blasted through the regular business, with some minor delays during a slightly more free-form portion of lodge, and then got to the presentation of the Travel Gavel. Unfortunately, I don&#8217;t have pictures of that, since we were in open lodge at the time (meaning photography is verboten), but it was wonderful. In addition to the travel gavel on the plaque, Fort Worth Lodge has decided to toss in the Mega Gavel as well. Now, in addition to the <a href="http://www.64th.org/traveling-gavel-rules/">existing stipulations</a> on the gavel, the Mega Gavel will be travelling with the regular plaque. After our <a href="http://www.handonahkur.com/">Brother Hando Nahkur</a> played a very stirring piece, we closed out and Hollywooded for the camera. All in all, a great night in Texas Masonry.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>A group photo (most of us are in here):</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://texanmason.com/images/20170313-group.jpg" alt="20170313 group.jpg">
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>14 of the 15 brothers from Handley, with guest appearance by the Mega Gavel (Worshipful Master of Handley Lodge, Haskell Rogers III, is in the middle with the plaque):</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://texanmason.com/images/20170313-handley.jpg" alt="20170313 handley.jpg">
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Our pro-tem WM Greg Wright (on the left) poses with some of our brothers from Webb Lodge! We really hope that they are the next ones to get the gavel. Ed (on the right) is a Past Master of both Webb Lodge and Handley Lodge:</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://texanmason.com/images/20170313-webb.jpg" alt="20170313 webb.jpg">
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Life is good.</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://texanmason.com/2017/03/13/Handley-Lodge-Captures-the-Travel-Gavel.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://texanmason.com/2017/03/13/Handley-Lodge-Captures-the-Travel-Gavel.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Freemason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Free]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Masonry]]></category><category><![CDATA[Craft]]></category><category><![CDATA[Blue]]></category><category><![CDATA[Lodge]]></category><category><![CDATA[Handley]]></category><category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category><category><![CDATA[Gavel]]></category><category><![CDATA[Fraternity]]></category><category><![CDATA[Competition]]></category><pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Fourth Podcast Episode]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>Please join us this week in our fireside chat as we talk about what it means to walk and act as a Mason. What&#8217;s the deal with charity? How to you make sure that you&#8217;re still in touch with your morals? How do we apply the idea of the cornerstone of a building to ourselves? Brothers Rhit Moore, Grant Gates, and Gabriel Jagush get wonderfully sidetracked for a bit on news and then get to work (we get started on the main subject at around the 24 minute mark). Afterwards, tune in (1 hr 18 min mark) for listing of local events.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><a href="http://fortworth148.libsyn.com/004-ever-to-walk-and-act-as-such"><em>Ever to Walk and Act as Such - What&#8217;s it mean to act like a Mason, anyway?</em></a></p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://texanmason.com/2017/03/09/Fourth-Podcast-Episode.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://texanmason.com/2017/03/09/Fourth-Podcast-Episode.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Freemason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Free]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Masonry]]></category><category><![CDATA[Craft]]></category><category><![CDATA[Blue]]></category><category><![CDATA[Lodge]]></category><category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category><category><![CDATA[Fort]]></category><category><![CDATA[Worth]]></category><category><![CDATA[148]]></category><pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Third Podcast Episode]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>Third podcast episode is up! Super late on the draw on actually updating my site. It&#8217;s been kind of hectic - recent change of employment.</p>
</div>
<div class="quoteblock">
<blockquote>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Brothers Rhit Moore, Grant Gates, and Gabriel Jagush get to talking about what it means to provide value to a lodge. Are you getting your money&#8217;s worth? Can you improve your lodge? What are you doing right? What about your wife? We also get sidetracked on the dreaded subject of dues for a bit.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>We continue with more information on the Italian Affair, discuss a recent arson attack on our Brothers in Canada, a masonic children&#8217;s home saved from closure, and the renovation of the Colored Masonic Building in Birmingham, AL. At the end of the episode, we talk about what&#8217;s going on in the 64th district of Texas.</p>
</div>
</blockquote>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><a href="http://fortworth148.libsyn.com/episode-003-building-value"><em>Building Value - Let&#8217;s make it worth your time</em></a>.</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://texanmason.com/2017/03/06/Third-Podcast-Episode.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://texanmason.com/2017/03/06/Third-Podcast-Episode.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Freemason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Free]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Masonry]]></category><category><![CDATA[Craft]]></category><category><![CDATA[Blue]]></category><category><![CDATA[Lodge]]></category><category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category><category><![CDATA[Fort]]></category><category><![CDATA[Worth]]></category><category><![CDATA[148]]></category><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Second Podcast Episode]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>Second episode is up! It&#8217;s a triple-threat this week at the Fort Worth 148 Podcast as Brothers Rhit Moore, Grant Gates, and Gabriel Jagush talk about guarding the West Gate. It&#8217;s not fun to say, but masonry isn&#8217;t for everyone. How do you best get to know the man you want to call brother? Is he the right fit for Freemasonry, and is Freemasonry the right fit for him? How do you investigate him? These are all questions we explore in this episode. We also briefly touch on the issues our Italian brothers are experiencing, and the Florida/Cuba Grand Lodge drama. At the end of the episode, we have an update on events in and around us, so if you&#8217;re short on time, but want to know what&#8217;s going on in the 64th district, please check out the last few minutes of the podcast and we&#8217;ll get you updated.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><a href="http://www.stitcher.com/s?eid=49226934"><em>Guarding the West Gate</em></a></p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://texanmason.com/2017/02/23/Second-Podcast-Episode.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://texanmason.com/2017/02/23/Second-Podcast-Episode.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Freemason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Free]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Masonry]]></category><category><![CDATA[Craft]]></category><category><![CDATA[Blue]]></category><category><![CDATA[Lodge]]></category><category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category><category><![CDATA[Fort]]></category><category><![CDATA[Worth]]></category><category><![CDATA[148]]></category><pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Quest for Judas Maccabeus]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>Founder of the Order of Judas Maccabeus, Brother Herman Sarachan:</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://texanmason.com/images/20170220-img1.jpg" alt="Herman Sarachan">
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>My latest obsession is one that I&#8217;ve touched on before in <a href="/posts/20170112.html">the article I shared</a> by R∴W∴ Raymond Beardsley. For those of you that have not yet heard of the Order of Judas Maccabeus, it was an order founded in New York State by a group of brothers seeking a non-Christian alternative to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Knights_Templar_(Freemasonry)">Commandery</a>. The founding of the Order did involve Masons from many aspects of the Craft, including representatives and leaders from the NYS grand bodies of Chapter, Council, and Commandery.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>One of my goals has been to reach out to brothers that were involved in the Order. This has proved to be very difficult. Many of the men involved in OoJM have passed away, or don&#8217;t have an online presence, which makes reaching out a lot more difficult! When I first read the article by Brother Beardsley, I figured that I should try and see if I could contact him. That is when I found out that he had passed away about two weeks before I had found the article. No luck there, unfortunately, and may Brother Beardsley rest easy in the arms of the Creator.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Initially, I thought I had reached a dead end. However, having read the article, I had a jumping-off point: the home Chapter and home Council of the OoJM founder, Brother Herman Sarachan. I sent out emails to the recorder of Doric Council #19 and to the recorder of Hiram Chapter #62. My email to Hiram Chapter was a little bit of a Hail Mary, because I wasn&#8217;t sure if this was a reformation of Hamilton Chapter, or if it was a different entity entirely. As of yet, I still have to hear back from their recorder, so my assumption is that it is a different Chapter entirely.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>However, I was able to hear back from Brother John Dudley, the Recorder of Doric Council (also the Secretary of Northfield Lodge #426). He informed me that he had been a member of the Order and had watched it slowly die. At the time of his joining, he was the 71st member of the Genesee Valley Assemblage #1, which is is shown on the scan of his last dues card for the Order, which he sent to me:</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://texanmason.com/images/20170220-img2.jpg" alt="20170220 img2.jpg">
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Brother Dudley then put me in contact with (R∴W∴) Brother John Gallant, who was not a member of the Order, but had been in contact with Brother Beardsley. I emailed Brother Gallant to talk to him and see what I could learn, and ended up with an incredible surprise. Not only did Brother Gallant inform me that there was an Assemblage operating in Texas, he sent me a copy of the Texas ritual! I don&#8217;t feel comfortable posting/sharing the ritual in such an accessible format, so I will try to describe the document. The "Standard Work" was written by Brother Sarachan in 1974 in New York State, and the Texas ritual&#8217;s latest revision, according to the document, was in August 2007, by the late Brother Cliff Cameron. Brother Cameron was a Knight of the York Cross of Honor, and the 2007 Grand Historian of the <a href="http://www.yorkritetexas.org/council/">Grand Council of Royal and Select Masters of Texas</a>.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The Order conferred two degrees, the <em>Order of David</em> and the <em>Order of Judas Maccabeus</em>. There would have been a third order, the <em>Order of the Temple</em>, but Brother Sarachan died before he could finish it. From what I have been told, my understanding is that there were/are some efforts to finish the Order of the Temple, but I cannot verify this.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The Order of David teaches the lessons of love and devotion through the story of Jonathan and David planning David&#8217;s escape from King Saul&#8217;s grasp. The degree opens the Volume of Sacred Law (VSL) to <em>Samuel 1 18:1</em>. The officers of the Order of David are:</p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Sovereign Master</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Companion Senior Warden</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Companion Junior Warden</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Companion Captain of the Guard</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Companion Marshall</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Companion Warder</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Companion Sentinel</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>After the candidate is made a Companion of the Order of David and has observed the drama, the new Companion retires without the Assemblage&#8217;s room, and the Assemblage resumes labor in the Order of Judas Maccabeus, due to having called down to the Order of David for the purpose of conferral, and the Companion is made a Valiant Prince. The Order of Judas Maccabeus teaches the lessons of fidelity and devotion (to faith) through the story of the Maccabean revolt against the Hellenistic regime of Antiochus IV. The degree opens the VSL to either <em>Psalm 23</em> or <em>Ecclesiastes 12</em>. The officers of the Order of Judas Maccabeus are:</p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Sovereign Prince Commander</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Valiant Prince Chancellor</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Valiant Prince Orator</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Valiant Prince Cohen</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Valiant Prince Treasurer</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Valiant Prince Recorder</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Valiant Prince Captain of the Guard</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Valiant Prince Marshall</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Valiant Prince Warder</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Valiant Prince Sentinel</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>They are seated in the Assemblage room as such:</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://texanmason.com/images/20170220-img3.jpg" alt="20170220 img3.jpg">
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>There, dear readers, is where I had to go from. My next step was to find out how to contact Brother Cameron, so I reached out to the Grand Recorder of the Grand Council of Texas. I was informed that he had passed away, but that there was a Grand Chapter/Council History and Preservation Committee. I have yet to hear back from either of the emails that I sent to the committee members, unfortunately. I also reached out to the Grand College of Rites, as I am a member ("Fellow"). No dice there, either. Radio silence.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>At this point, I think I stalled out for a two weeks, because I was pretty stumped about what to do next. I talked about it with my brothers in lodge, and online, on Reddit, etc, etc, etc. It was then that someone suggested that I email Brother Arturo de Hoyos, who is an expert historian on most anything and everything Masonic. Brother de Hoyos was very friendly and informed me that this was actually an avenue of investigation that one of his associates was pursuing! The running theory is that the group is totally defunct. If so, the rituals will be printed as <a href="http://grandcollegeofrites.org/collectanea/">Collectanea</a> for the Grand College of Rites. I emailed him what I had in terms of general materials, contact information, and so forth. Hopefully something will turn up soon!</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In the meanwhile, I am continuing my search. I&#8217;m not sure where this will lead me. Honestly, I am really hoping that there&#8217;s still an active Assemblage somewhere in Texas. All you would need is to to grab five companions of the Royal Arch, and then have them inducted into the Order. That being the required number of Valiant Princes for an Assemblage to form and meet, perhaps there is hope for the future of Judas Maccabeus?</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://texanmason.com/2017/02/20/A-New-Obsession.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://texanmason.com/2017/02/20/A-New-Obsession.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Freemason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Free]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Masonry]]></category><category><![CDATA[Craft]]></category><category><![CDATA[Blue]]></category><category><![CDATA[Lodge]]></category><category><![CDATA[York]]></category><category><![CDATA[Rite]]></category><category><![CDATA[Jewish]]></category><category><![CDATA[Knights]]></category><category><![CDATA[Knight]]></category><category><![CDATA[Templar]]></category><category><![CDATA[Alternative]]></category><category><![CDATA[Judas]]></category><category><![CDATA[Maccabeus]]></category><category><![CDATA[Judah]]></category><category><![CDATA[Maccabee]]></category><pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[First Podcast Episode]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>Well then, here we go. Jumping into the deep end with my lodge brother, Rhit Moore. We have decided to revive the Fort Worth 148 Podcast. Let&#8217;s see how this goes! Our goal is to do good work, spread news for the Craft, and get nerdy as hell real quick. Check out our first episode, <a href="http://www.stitcher.com/podcast/fort-worth-148""><em>Tech and the Lodge</em></a>.</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://texanmason.com/2017/02/17/First-Podcast-Episode.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://texanmason.com/2017/02/17/First-Podcast-Episode.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Freemason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Free]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Masonry]]></category><category><![CDATA[Craft]]></category><category><![CDATA[Blue]]></category><category><![CDATA[Lodge]]></category><category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category><category><![CDATA[Fort]]></category><category><![CDATA[Worth]]></category><category><![CDATA[148]]></category><pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Traveling Gavel]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>The Grand Lodge of Texas (AF&amp;AM) 64th District Traveling Gavel:</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://texanmason.com/images/20170209-img1.jpg" alt="20170209 img1.jpg">
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Tonight we had the privilege of visiting Handley Lodge. It was a pretty great experience! They had, up to this point, been the holders of the GLoTX 64th District Traveling Gavel. This was a program that was originally started by my lodge (148). In order to capture the gavel, your lodge has to show up with 7 or more brothers. The visit can be either during a stated meeting, or a called meeting. If  multiple lodge attempt a capture, whichever lodge has the most lodges present takes it home, with a coin toss being the  method used to break ties.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The brothers from Handley welcomed us with open arms and we had an absolutely great time. This was a very well-attended stated meeting! Even Arlington Lodge (438, I think) sent a contingent of brothers in their own attempt to make a capture. At one point, someone from Sweet Home Lodge tried to see if there were enough plural members of Sweet Home Lodoge for them to take it! That would have been a very difficult retrieval as they only open lodge in the Master&#8217;s Degree, and as such, would require us to send only our Master Masons.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The food was great - the OES chapter at Handley really knows how to knock it out of the park.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Here we are with the Worshipful Master of Handley Lodge, Haskell Rogers (III):</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://texanmason.com/images/20170209-img2.jpg" alt="20170209 img2.jpg">
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Bonus picture of our group in front of the very-appropriate "COME AND TAKE IT" flag:</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://texanmason.com/images/20170209-img3.jpg" alt="20170209 img3.jpg">
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>For more information on the Traveling Gavel, check out the <a href="http://www.64th.org/traveling-gavel-rules/">64th district&#8217;s page on it</a>. I sincerely urge anyone in the 64th district to "COME AND TAKE IT," so to speak, as we will try our damndest to take it right back.</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://texanmason.com/2017/02/09/Competitive-Brotherhood.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://texanmason.com/2017/02/09/Competitive-Brotherhood.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Freemason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Free]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Masonry]]></category><category><![CDATA[Craft]]></category><category><![CDATA[Blue]]></category><category><![CDATA[Lodge]]></category><pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA["The Order of Judas Maccabeus" by R∴W∴ Raymond Beardsly]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div id="preamble">
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I was trying to find out some more info about this Order when it came up a couple of days ago. Found a PDF called "The Pyramid Texts" and figured it would be useful to have this in a more web-friendly format.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>If you want to read more articles like this, I think that the Philalethes Society actually offers an optional CD with a massive back catalogue of articles.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_the_order_of_judas_maccabeus">THE ORDER OF JUDAS MACCABEUS</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p><strong>Raymond R. Beardsley</strong></p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><strong>The Philalethes - October 1991</strong></p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In the mid-1970&#8217;s, a group of York Rite Masons met in the Rochester area of upstate New York to consider the initiation of a new organization with the purpose of eventually proposing it as a new Body to be incorporated in the York Rite of Freemasonry. The inception of this idea had emanated from the fertile brain of the late Brother Herman Sarachan, often referred to as Mr. Mason in the Rochester area. Brother Sarachan had a distinguished Masonic record, having actively participated in both the Scottish and York Rites, as well as having served as a District Deputy Grand Master in the Monroe County area. He had been the High Priest of Hamilton Chapter #62 and the Illustrious Master of Doric Council #19.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>For many years, Brother Sarachan edited a column in the Monroe Masonic News (the monthly Masonic publication in the Rochester area) entitled: "Dear Brother Herman," in which he answered questions regarding Masonry - history, biography, definition, procedure, law, ritual, protocol, etc. His articles were later incorporated into a book under the same title, published in 1979; in addition, Brother Sarachan had previously published a book on the history of Freemasonry in the Rochester and Monroe County area of New York.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Brother Sarachan believed that there was a need for an additional body in the York Rite for those Masons who either could not for religious reasons or would not for personal reasons join the Commandery of Knights Templar. The first two York Rite Bodies, the Royal Arch Chapter and the Council of Cryptic Masons, like the Symbolic Lodge, are non-sectarian; however, the Commandery of Knights Templar is distinctly a Christian Order of Masonry and is also a military-type organization with uniforms, drills and inspections. As a result, Members of the Chapter and Council who are not Christians or who do not favor the militaristic atmosphere of the Commandery do not have a comparable body to join, which would be more suitable to their religious or personal beliefs and mores. With this in mind, Brother Sarachan proposed that a new body be initiated to meet the needs and desires of these particular Masonic Brethren but which would welcome all Masons who wished to participate. The organization would be known as The Order of Judas Maccabeus.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Judas Maccabeus was the renowned leader of the Jews when they revolted against Roman hegemony in the second century, B.C., particularly after the Romans had desecrated the Temple at Jerusalem by erecting a statue of Zeus over the altar. Under the leadership of Judas Maccabeus, the Jews regained control of Jerusalem and the Temple for a period of time celebrated in Jewish history. Because of his prestige and stature in Hebrew history and tradition, the name of Judas Maccabeus was considered most appropriate for the new body. The Order of Judas Maccabeus would be founded on a non-sectarian basis and without military accouterments, with the goal that it would eventually become a parallel Body to the Commandery.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Thus, in 1974, a group of some 30 York Rite leaders in the local area met in the Rochester Temple to formally consider The Order of Judas Maccabeus. Present were Masons prominent in all the York Rite Bodies, including past heads of all of the Grand Bodies in the State of New York: M∴ E∴ Frank Allen of the Grand Chapter, M∴ I∴ Bruce Dayton of the Grand Council and R∴ E∴ Ward Ekas of the Grand Commandery. All in attendance were unanimously in agreement as to the desirability of instituting a complementary Body to the Commandery that would more appropriately meet the needs of our Jewish and other non-Christian or non-military-minded Companions. It should be born in mind that the majority of York Rite Masons present were Christians and members of the local Commanderies.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The Order of Judas Maccabeus was originally to encompass three Orders: The Order of David, The Order of Judas Maccabeus and The Order of the Temple (referring to the Jewish Temple). The Order of David teaches the lesson of unselfish love and devotion and uses as its framework the story of David and Jonathan, as depicted in the Old Testament in the Book of First Samuel. The Order of Judas Maccabeus teaches the lesson of fidelity and devotion to faith and uses as its framework the revolt of the Jews in 168 B.C. against the Roman hierarchy of Antiochus, who had prohibited the practice of the Jewish faith and had desecrated the Temple, as related in the Apocryphal Books of the Maccabeus.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>These first two Orders were prepared under the aegis of Brother Sarachan, and, to date, have formed the basis for initiation into the Order. The Order of the Temple, which ultimately is to form the final phase of initiation into the Order, has not been completed. Brother Sarachan&#8217;s health failed and he passed on before he could turn his attention to the proposed Order of the Temple. However, it is now in the process of formulation, and much thought is going into its preparation, in order that it may take its place on a level with such awe-inspiring exemplifications as the Royal Arch Degree of the Chapter, the Super Excellent Degree of the Council and the Order of the Temple of the Commandery.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Members of The Order of Judas Maccabeus are titled "Valiant Princes" and constituent Bodies are termed "Assemblages," whose principal officers are Commander, Chancellor, Orator, Treasurer, Recorder, Captain of the Guard, Lecturer, Marshall, Warden and Sentinel. The premier Assemblage, inaugurated in the Rochester area, is known as Genesee Valley Assemblage #1.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>A number of other Assemblages have been instituted in New York State, specifically in New York, Long Island and Buffalo. Also, Assemblages have been inaugurated in the States of Connecticut and New Jersey. Numerous inquiries have been received from interested York Rite Masons from such States as Ohio, Michigan, Wisconsin, Arizona and California, to name a few.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Although the early years of Genesee Valley Assemblage #1 did not always run smoothly and for awhile the original enthusiasm was somewhat abated, it is now prospering with a large number of new members. Whereas the charter membership was largely Christian, in recent years a number of our Jewish and other non-Christian Brethren have joined. In the meantime, with the emergence of other Assemblages about New York and adjoining States, a Grand Assemblage was instituted a few years ago with the presiding officer designated to be "The Most Sovereign Grand Commander of North America."</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Any inquiries and questions should be forwarded to the above address. Although there may be those who question the desirability of a new Masonic organization, the criterion that should be applied is the need for and function of such a new Masonic entity. Over the past 35 years, we have experienced the inception of two new Masonic organizations which met specific needs and desires and, as a result, have been highly successful. These are The York Rite Sovereign College of North America and The National Camping Travelers. The first originated for Masons active in all four York Rite Bodies, and the second for Masons and their families interested in camping. Both of these Masonic organization have, in a relatively few years, grown tremendously with both of them having well over 100 constituent Bodies throughout the United States and Canada.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In like manner, The Order of Judas Maccabeus was founded to meet a distinct need in York Rite Masonry. Because of this, those of us who have been intimately connected with its formulation and establishment feel that it will play a unique and increasingly important role in The York Rite of Freemasonry.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><strong><em>Raymond R. Beardsley (December 8, 1925 - December 28, 2016)</em></strong> <em>was a member and Past Master of Northfield Lodge #426 F. &amp; A.M. in Pittsford, NY. He was the Past Most Illustrious Grand Master of the Grand Council of the State of New York, Past District Deputy Grand High Priest, Past Commander of Cyrene-Monroe Commandery #12, and Past District Deputy Grand Master 2nd Monroe District. He was a Scottish Rite Mason and a member of Damascus Shrine in Webster, NY.</em></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>http://texanmason.com/2017/01/12/Swords-and-Jesus-no-Swords-and-Jews-yes.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://texanmason.com/2017/01/12/Swords-and-Jesus-no-Swords-and-Jews-yes.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Freemason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Free]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Masonry]]></category><category><![CDATA[Craft]]></category><category><![CDATA[Blue]]></category><category><![CDATA[Lodge]]></category><category><![CDATA[York]]></category><category><![CDATA[Rite]]></category><category><![CDATA[Jewish]]></category><category><![CDATA[Knights]]></category><category><![CDATA[Knight]]></category><category><![CDATA[Templar]]></category><category><![CDATA[Alternative]]></category><category><![CDATA[Judas]]></category><category><![CDATA[Maccabeus]]></category><category><![CDATA[Judah]]></category><category><![CDATA[Maccabee]]></category><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Rant on Degree Work]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>If you volunteer for a part in a degree, you should actually know that part and be able to deliver it.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>We had an FC degree today for an EA who has been waiting quite a while. Very happy for him since he has been putting a lot of effort into the work. I had been reading up on the JW position in case we needed to fill in chairs since I had heard we were going to be a lighter crowd that usual - I usually play the part of the JD because I like to play with light switches.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I was initially slated to be the JW pro-tem, but was shortly told that I would be JD, as one of our older brothers from out of state had asked to contribute to the degree. Not a big deal, since he&#8217;s older and doesn&#8217;t get to do much, so I stepped aside, but in the interest of full disclosure, I really actually was pretty excited to sit in the South for this degree, and was kind of bummed out. However, <a href="https://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=Genesis+1%3A1-3&amp;version=KJV">I do like light switches&#8230;&#8203;</a></p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Anyway, this fellow was raised in a different state (now has our lodge as a "home base" of sorts), and is even a PM, but different states are different states, so he was asked if he knew the lines for Texas' ritual. He said "no," so I played SD to his JW while one of our older members, Centenarian Brother (turning 100 in a few months!) fed him lines. We did this a couple of times, and the delivery was&#8230;&#8203; shaky at best. He is older, has memory issues, and his speech is very difficult to decipher. However, he was really wanting to do the part, so we went ahead.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Right before the degree, our SW pro-tem leaned over to me and expressed his concerns about the South. Another red flag, I suppose. The degree happens, and sure enough, he forgot every line, had to be prompted more than once per line on multiple occasions, and forgot to display the DG &amp; PS after the obligation while the WM and SW next to him were displaying them. There was a quiet groan from our SW at one point.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>While the candidate was back in the prep room, I went over the lines with him, again playing the part of SD while Centenarian Brother taught him his lines. Again, same deal. The same thing happened during closing. It was incredibly frustrating to watch.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>After the lodge closed and the acting JW had left, the SW went on a short, quiet rant to a few people that ended with "this was a disaster."</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I am salty? A little bit. I don&#8217;t if it&#8217;s without merit, though.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>So please, folks, if you know your lines, by all means, please, help out. If you don&#8217;t, please come to floor school, or observe degrees, or both. I love floor school. I love degrees. I would go and do every day if I had the time.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>TL;DR: I&#8217;m whinging on the internet, I suppose. Please forgive me.</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://texanmason.com/2016/11/29/Gabe-loses-his-Compasses-for-a-bit.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://texanmason.com/2016/11/29/Gabe-loses-his-Compasses-for-a-bit.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Freemason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Free]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Masonry]]></category><category><![CDATA[Craft]]></category><category><![CDATA[Blue]]></category><category><![CDATA[Lodge]]></category><category><![CDATA[Ritual]]></category><category><![CDATA[Memory]]></category><category><![CDATA[Acting]]></category><category><![CDATA[Performance]]></category><category><![CDATA[Knowledge]]></category><pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Bad Linguistics]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div id="preamble">
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p><em>This was originally posted to a private lodge Facebook group for Fort Worth Lodge #148.</em></p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Recently, I tried to translate "Mind and Conscience" into both Latin and Hebrew. The Latin translation was very easy: <strong>mens et conscientia.</strong> Hey, you can see how similar it is, right? When it came to Hebrew, I didn&#8217;t get to "conscience" for a long time because of the rabbit hole that "mind" lead down. The Hebrew word for "conscience," by the way, is מַצְפּוּן or <strong>matspon</strong>, which means "conscience" or "scruple," and anciently meant "hidden treasure." That&#8217;s a discussion for another time, I think.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>So, anyway, what <em>does</em> the word "mind" look like in Hebrew?</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Well, that&#8217;s not a simple question with a simple answer. Both in contemporary Hebrew and the Hebrew of the Tanakh / Old Testament, there are many words which are translated to English and the Romance languages as "mind," but do not actually have the <strong>meaning</strong> of "mind." You see, the word "mind," as we understand it in English, is uniquely colored by the fact that it is a Romance language word.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In Spanish (and Portuguese &amp; Italian) we say "mente," in Romanian, it&#8217;s "minte," and so forth. However, this isn&#8217;t shared into other language families, or regions, or even into other Romance languages! In French (Romance language family), for example, the word is "espirit" from the Latin "spiritus" ("breath," "breeze," or "ghost"). In German (different language family, same region) it&#8217;s "Geist" which means "spirit" first, then "ghost," then "mind."</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Then we get to the Semitic language family. Whole different ballgame, folks. As far as I can tell, there is no one word in Hebrew that, strictly speaking, <strong>actually</strong> means "mind" as we understand it, only words that can be acceptably substituted. I have compiled a small list of them, and what I&#8217;ve learned about them. Some of these words were used anciently in the Tanakh / Old Testament, and some of these are more contemporary. My apologies to any of our brethren who may take offense to the writing of the Tetragrammaton; I hope I have done this respectfully in an academic context.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_heart">Heart - לבב</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The word לב or <strong>leb</strong> (also לבב or <strong>lebab</strong>) refers to the literal organ of the heart, with secondary, figurative meaning as the seat of emotions and appetites, specifically that of Courage. It can also mean "inner person" or "[the] will."</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_spirit">Spirit - רוח</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Another possible translation is רוח or <strong>ruach</strong>. It primarily means "wind," but it can also mean "breath." It has a tertiary meaning of "spirit" (but still not "mind").</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>It also has a prophetic form, רוח הקודש (<strong>ruach</strong> <strong>hakodesh</strong>), which is the name of the Holy Spirit in the Tanakh. There are other forms &amp; words of which <strong>ruach</strong> is a component. רוח אלוהים (<strong>ruach</strong> <strong>Elohim</strong>) and רוח-אל (<strong>ruach-El</strong>) also refer to the Spirit of God. רוח יהוה (<strong>ruach</strong> <strong>Adonai</strong>) means "The Spirit of the Lord" and רוח אדני יהוה (<strong>ruach</strong> <strong>Adonai</strong> <strong>Adonai</strong>) means "The Spirit of the Lord God," which are both commonly and improperly translated as "The Sprit of Jehovah" and "The Spirit of the Lord Jehovah," respectively. The YHWH discussion is a whole different rabbit-hole.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_soul">Soul - נפש</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The spirit of a person or an animal is נפש or <strong>nepesh</strong>, which is directly translated as "soul." It can also mean "life," refer to a person / human being, or will/intent. It also has an antiquated meaning of "breath," which reminds us of רוח / ruah. It can be used to define life and consciousness as we understand it in humans and animals of higher intelligence, which is a very close approximation (but not exact) of "mind."</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_marrow">Marrow - מֹחַ</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>More commonly spelled מוֹחַ, but anciently מֹחַ or <strong>moach</strong>, this word is biblically used to refer to bone marrow (and still is in some contexts), and more recently, primarily in reference to the brain. It closely relates to <strong>ruach</strong>, "spirit."</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_consciousness">Consciousness - תודעה</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>A closer word still is תודעה or <strong>toda&#8217;a</strong>, which can refer to an awareness or a consciousness. This is one of the most commonly used words to substitute for mind, but still isn&#8217;t a catch-all. The "mind-body problem," for example, is the "guf-<strong>nepesh</strong> problem," while something like "a state of mind" is translated as "a state of <strong>toda&#8217;a</strong>."</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_reason">Reason - תבונה</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The word תבונה or <strong>tevunah</strong> primarily stands for "reason." It can also stand for a wisdom, or intelligence. The word for "understanding" is derived from <strong>tevunah</strong>. The words for prudence, discreetness, knowledge, etc, are also derivations of this word. In <em>Mishlei</em>/Proverbs 3:19-20, we read:</p>
</div>
<div class="quoteblock">
<blockquote>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>"<em>Hashem</em> / God laid the earth&#8217;s foundations with wisdom (<strong>chochmah</strong>), by understanding (<strong>tevunah</strong>) he set the heavens in place; through His knowledge (<strong>daat</strong>) the depths were cleaved, and the clouds let drop the dew."&lt;/i&gt;</p>
</div>
</blockquote>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In this case, Rabbeinu Yonah explains that <strong>chochmah</strong> is the lowest form of learning - the information that is conveyed to you from someone else. <strong>tevunah</strong> is the information or understanding that one arrives to after meditating upon the <strong>chochmah</strong> one has been taught.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_intelligence">Intelligence - שכל</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Shared in Hebrew and Yiddish with slightly different meanings, שכל or <strong>sechel</strong> means intelligence, brains, wisdom, or in wisdom. Recently, it has also come to refer to common sense and "smarts." However, it doesn&#8217;t just quite translate to any of those, just like "mind" doesn&#8217;t translate to it or the other previously-discussed words. In older Hebrew usage, the word had very serious moral and ethical connotations that it does not really have today. In contemporary Yiddish, the word denotes a very respected quality regarding one&#8217;s pursuit of knowledge and ability to leave the world a better place.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>As you can see, there&#8217;s no one word that means exactly what we conceive of as "mind." This is not uncommon, as many languages have words that don&#8217;t quite translate well, like the Portuguese "saudade," the Spanish "sobremesa," the German "Weltschmerz," etc. The closest word, in my opinion, appears to be תודעה (<strong>toda&#8217;a</strong>), which is most commonly used in contemporary Hebrew. Other words I found to be close in the semitic language family are שכל (<strong>sechel</strong>, Yiddish for "understanding," shared with Hebrew but with a slightly different meaning), and عقل (<strong>eaql</strong>, Arabic for "reason").</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_online_resources">Online resources:</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/%D7%9C%D7%91" class="bare">https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/%D7%9C%D7%91</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/%D7%A8%D7%95%D7%97" class="bare">https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/%D7%A8%D7%95%D7%97</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/%D7%A0%D7%A4%D7%A9" class="bare">https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/%D7%A0%D7%A4%D7%A9</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://torah.org/torah-portion/hamaayan-5769-bereishis/" class="bare">https://torah.org/torah-portion/hamaayan-5769-bereishis/</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/%D7%A9%D7%9B%D7%9C" class="bare">https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/%D7%A9%D7%9B%D7%9C</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://www.momentmag.com/jewish-word-sechel/" class="bare">http://www.momentmag.com/jewish-word-sechel/</a></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>http://texanmason.com/2016/10/26/Gabe-engages-in-shoddy-academics.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://texanmason.com/2016/10/26/Gabe-engages-in-shoddy-academics.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Freemason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Free]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Masonry]]></category><category><![CDATA[Craft]]></category><category><![CDATA[Blue]]></category><category><![CDATA[Lodge]]></category><category><![CDATA[Hebrew]]></category><category><![CDATA[Latin]]></category><category><![CDATA[Translate]]></category><category><![CDATA[Translation]]></category><pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA["...but he needs knowledge of the TRUE secrets of Freemasonry."]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>I attended a function recently as the guest of one of my Brothers, along with a MM from one of my sister lodges. Was not able to attend the meeting itself, obviously, but was allowed to join in for a hearty dinner and listen to a pretty good talk on the book of Ecclesiastes. Fascinating stuff. Shook a lot of hands, met a lot of new people.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Anyway, I had two exchanges, one short and one long/frustrating, with Brothers I already know. The short one feels like it played into the longer one.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>After the dinner, I talked to a Brother I knew, commenting on how well we had been received. "Oh, absolutely, I had no doubt that you&#8217;d love it. [NSAB] is the best, friendliest body in all the Fraternity. You just can&#8217;t compare." I brushed this one off because we had very definitely been greeted with open arms. I didn&#8217;t even think about this until I was meditating on the other exchange.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The other exchange was with a Brother who I know even better. He&#8217;s a very influential brother in our Temple. We&#8217;d been talking about different opportunities in the appendant bodies after my raising. He&#8217;s very keen on seeing people join [NSAB], which is great, and I plan to join it eventually, but I also want to take some time and "soak" in Blue Lodge. We talked about our line officers and I mentioned how outstanding I think our JW has been.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>This is when things started to get more frustrating. This line got busted out (paraphrased from memory): "Well, he&#8217;s a very innate leader, and I&#8217;m very proud of him, but he doesn&#8217;t know the <em>true</em> secrets of Freemasonry. If he&#8217;s going to be an effective leader, he needs to ask more questions about what happened in his Master&#8217;s Degree, and have them answered, and he can only do that in [NSAB]. That&#8217;s where he&#8217;ll gain leadership skills, too. Ninety percent of what you hear in the Blue Lodge is bullshit unless you follow up on it elsewhere. We have the answers. You can&#8217;t be a good Officer without having learned from [NSAB], and when you sit in the chairs, I want you have done that first. You&#8217;ll gain a lot of leadership skills that you need if you do that before getting in the chairs." This is a sentiment I have heard before from a lot of older Brothers in [NSAB].</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I was pretty frustrated by that. Right now, none of our line officers have been through any of the appendant bodies, including some that have been in Lodge for a while now, and the vast majority of them have been doing an incredible job. We have some BLO guys, but we also have some that are considering joining up with the appendant bodies when it&#8217;s the right time. I feel like it&#8217;s very dismissive from my Brothers in the appendant bodies to place so much emphasis on things outside of Blue Lodge in specific relation to the running of the Blue Lodge.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I&#8217;m neither really hear nor there on the appendant bodies, because I&#8217;m really interested, but I want to wait for a while, and I have no plans or machinations set on getting into the Chairs because it is <em>waaaaaaay</em> too early for me to have that kind of discussion. I just feel like this a really common sort of sentiment among guys in appendant bodies, and that it&#8217;s incredibly dismissive/disrespectful of Craft Lodge in general.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Am I out of line in feeling a little miffed about this? I don&#8217;t know for sure, but I am.</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://texanmason.com/2016/10/21/Today-in-My-Brothers-in-Non-Specified-Appendant-Body-are-Driving-Me-Up-the-Wall.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://texanmason.com/2016/10/21/Today-in-My-Brothers-in-Non-Specified-Appendant-Body-are-Driving-Me-Up-the-Wall.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Freemason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Free]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Masonry]]></category><category><![CDATA[Craft]]></category><category><![CDATA[Blue]]></category><category><![CDATA[Lodge]]></category><category><![CDATA[Scottish]]></category><category><![CDATA[York]]></category><category><![CDATA[Rite]]></category><category><![CDATA[Shrine]]></category><category><![CDATA[Appendant]]></category><category><![CDATA[Body]]></category><category><![CDATA[Bodies]]></category><pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Prep Room]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p><em>This was originally posted to a private lodge Facebook group for Fort Worth Lodge #148.</em></p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><strong>These are some notes on a reddit comment by <a href="http://www.arslatomorum.com/vitae-maconarium/">V∴I∴ Brother Jason Mitchell</a>, on the subject of how the Room of Preparation should be set up. All I&#8217;ve done is format it for ease of reading.</strong></p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The Prep Room is ritual space. It is not a closet. It is not storage. It is not a utility room. It is just as "sacred" as the Lodge room proper, the altar, and the VSL itself. Clean out your prep room, and make it "sacred" ritual space.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The Prep Room experience is part of the ritual. It should be one candidate at a time (never exceed one candidate). It is not a locker room. The Candidate should feel midly unwelcome, and the Officers present need to be coldly professional and oppressively silent. There are no smiles in the prep room. There is no joviality in the prep room. Before the Candidate knocks on the door, he needs at least one heartbeat of hesitation and fear. He needs to look at the exit and make the choice to stay.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The prep room should be dark or dimly light. One light bulbs roughly 20W with a color temperature 2700-3000K (or LED or florescent equivalent) is enough. Bright bulbs, white bulbs, or colors are to be avoided. Candles are another matter, but most temples won&#8217;t cover the insurance for open flame.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Paint the town red. The prep room walls should be neither white nor black, but a neutral earth tone. With the proper illumination, the proper effect is achieved. Black and white walls ruin the effect. Neutral colors. Always use neutral colors in ritual environments. They just work better with illumination and colors, especially in low-light conditions.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Symbols. Only ever include symbols directly reference in your Grand Lodge&#8217;s Work, lectures, or monitors. The idea is to foreshadow things to come.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Know your work. It should go without saying that the prep room is the first ritual experience of the candidate. If you have to read the Work, you&#8217;ve already lost him.</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://texanmason.com/2016/10/05/Maybe-not-quite-the-Chamber-of-Reflection.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://texanmason.com/2016/10/05/Maybe-not-quite-the-Chamber-of-Reflection.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Freemason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Free]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Masonry]]></category><category><![CDATA[Craft]]></category><category><![CDATA[Blue]]></category><category><![CDATA[Lodge]]></category><category><![CDATA[Jason Mitchell]]></category><category><![CDATA[Prep]]></category><category><![CDATA[Room]]></category><category><![CDATA[Chamber]]></category><category><![CDATA[Reflection]]></category><pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Osirian Musings]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p><em>This was originally posted to a private lodge Facebook group for Fort Worth Lodge #148.</em></p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In the laundromat, I sat down to read a book that Rhit lent me (The Initiatic Experience) and while reading, I had an externally quiet, internally loud "A-HA!" moment.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In the second chapter (which is as far as I&#8217;ve gotten so far), there&#8217;s a lot of talk about the basics of the Egyptian death/afterlife mythos, including the resurrection/rebirth of Osiris, who was buried far in the West. After reading this, something kind of clicked for me and I tried to remember what I learned about Egypt in school!</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>According to the ancient Egyptians, the West was representative of Death. So much so, in fact, that people would traditionally build homes and regular temples on the East side of the Nile (the land of the living, where the Sun rose) instead of on the West side where tombs and funerary temples were built (the land of the dead, where the Sun set).</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In the Lodge, or at least in Texan Lodges (as well as many others, I&#8217;m sure), the door through which the candidate enters is on the western side of the room, just north of the Senior Warden&#8217;s chair. Here we see that he&#8217;s in a dark place, being on the "west bank" where the sun sets (as well as towards the North of the Lodge). By receiving the candidate, we bring him through the doors of the Lodge, from West to East.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Taking the West as Death, the direction of East as Life, and the doors as the barrier between those two worlds, not only is the candidate brought from darkness (western sunset) to light (eastern sunrise), but he is also reborn from death (west, outside the lodge room) to life (east, into the lodge room) as a new man and Mason.</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://texanmason.com/2016/09/20/Or-Reading-Too-Much-Into-Things.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://texanmason.com/2016/09/20/Or-Reading-Too-Much-Into-Things.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Freemason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Free]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Masonry]]></category><category><![CDATA[Osiris]]></category><category><![CDATA[Egypt]]></category><category><![CDATA[Death]]></category><category><![CDATA[Rebirth]]></category><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Evolution of Scottish Rite Masonry]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_complicated_flowcharts_scottish_rite_edition">Complicated flowcharts: Scottish Rite edition</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Original flowchart:</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://texanmason.com/images/20160919-img1.png" alt="Original flowchart">
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Cleaned-up version that I made:</p>
</div>
<div id="img-clean" class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<a class="image" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/gjagush/gjagush.github.io/master/images/20160919-img2.jpg"><img src="http://texanmason.com/images/20160919-img2.jpg" alt="Cleaned-Up Version"></a>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>http://texanmason.com/2016/09/19/Complicated-flowcharts-Scottish-Rite-edition.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://texanmason.com/2016/09/19/Complicated-flowcharts-Scottish-Rite-edition.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Freemason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Free]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Masonry]]></category><category><![CDATA[Craft]]></category><category><![CDATA[Blue]]></category><category><![CDATA[Lodge]]></category><category><![CDATA[Scottish Rite]]></category><category><![CDATA[Charts]]></category><category><![CDATA[Evolution]]></category><pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>