<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Untitled RSS Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Untitled RSS Feed]]></description><link>http://texanmason.com</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2017 19:04:42 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://texanmason.com/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[The Prep Room]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p><em>This was originally posted to a private lodge Facebook group for Fort Worth Lodge #148.</em></p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><strong>These are some notes on a reddit comment by <a href="http://www.arslatomorum.com/vitae-maconarium/">V∴I∴ Brother Jason Mitchell</a>, on the subject of how the Room of Preparation should be set up. All I&#8217;ve done is format it for ease of reading.</strong></p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The Prep Room is ritual space. It is not a closet. It is not storage. It is not a utility room. It is just as "sacred" as the Lodge room proper, the altar, and the VSL itself. Clean out your prep room, and make it "sacred" ritual space.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The Prep Room experience is part of the ritual. It should be one candidate at a time (never exceed one candidate). It is not a locker room. The Candidate should feel midly unwelcome, and the Officers present need to be coldly professional and oppressively silent. There are no smiles in the prep room. There is no joviality in the prep room. Before the Candidate knocks on the door, he needs at least one heartbeat of hesitation and fear. He needs to look at the exit and make the choice to stay.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The prep room should be dark or dimly light. One light bulbs roughly 20W with a color temperature 2700-3000K (or LED or florescent equivalent) is enough. Bright bulbs, white bulbs, or colors are to be avoided. Candles are another matter, but most temples won&#8217;t cover the insurance for open flame.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Paint the town red. The prep room walls should be neither white nor black, but a neutral earth tone. With the proper illumination, the proper effect is achieved. Black and white walls ruin the effect. Neutral colors. Always use neutral colors in ritual environments. They just work better with illumination and colors, especially in low-light conditions.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Symbols. Only ever include symbols directly reference in your Grand Lodge&#8217;s Work, lectures, or monitors. The idea is to foreshadow things to come.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Know your work. It should go without saying that the prep room is the first ritual experience of the candidate. If you have to read the Work, you&#8217;ve already lost him.</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://texanmason.com/2016/10/05/Maybe-not-quite-the-Chamber-of-Reflection.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://texanmason.com/2016/10/05/Maybe-not-quite-the-Chamber-of-Reflection.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Freemason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Free]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Masonry]]></category><category><![CDATA[Craft]]></category><category><![CDATA[Blue]]></category><category><![CDATA[Lodge]]></category><category><![CDATA[Jason Mitchell]]></category><category><![CDATA[Prep]]></category><category><![CDATA[Room]]></category><category><![CDATA[Chamber]]></category><category><![CDATA[Reflection]]></category><pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Osirian Musings]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p><em>This was originally posted to a private lodge Facebook group for Fort Worth Lodge #148.</em></p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In the laundromat, I sat down to read a book that Rhit lent me (The Initiatic Experience) and while reading, I had an externally quiet, internally loud "A-HA!" moment.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In the second chapter (which is as far as I&#8217;ve gotten so far), there&#8217;s a lot of talk about the basics of the Egyptian death/afterlife mythos, including the resurrection/rebirth of Osiris, who was buried far in the West. After reading this, something kind of clicked for me and I tried to remember what I learned about Egypt in school!</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>According to the ancient Egyptians, the West was representative of Death. So much so, in fact, that people would traditionally build homes and regular temples on the East side of the Nile (the land of the living, where the Sun rose) instead of on the West side where tombs and funerary temples were built (the land of the dead, where the Sun set).</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In the Lodge, or at least in Texan Lodges (as well as many others, I&#8217;m sure), the door through which the candidate enters is on the western side of the room, just north of the Senior Warden&#8217;s chair. Here we see that he&#8217;s in a dark place, being on the "west bank" where the sun sets (as well as towards the North of the Lodge). By receiving the candidate, we bring him through the doors of the Lodge, from West to East.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Taking the West as Death, the direction of East as Life, and the doors as the barrier between those two worlds, not only is the candidate brought from darkness (western sunset) to light (eastern sunrise), but he is also reborn from death (west, outside the lodge room) to life (east, into the lodge room) as a new man and Mason.</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://texanmason.com/2016/09/20/Or-Reading-Too-Much-Into-Things.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://texanmason.com/2016/09/20/Or-Reading-Too-Much-Into-Things.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Freemason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Free]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Masonry]]></category><category><![CDATA[Osiris]]></category><category><![CDATA[Egypt]]></category><category><![CDATA[Death]]></category><category><![CDATA[Rebirth]]></category><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Evolution of Scottish Rite Masonry]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_complicated_flowcharts_scottish_rite_edition">Complicated flowcharts: Scottish Rite edition</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Original flowchart:</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="http://texanmason.com/images/20160919-img1.png" alt="Original flowchart">
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Cleaned-up version that I made:</p>
</div>
<div id="img-clean" class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<a class="image" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/gjagush/gjagush.github.io/master/images/20160919-img2.jpg"><img src="http://texanmason.com/images/20160919-img2.jpg" alt="Cleaned-Up Version"></a>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>http://texanmason.com/2016/09/19/Complicated-flowcharts-Scottish-Rite-edition.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://texanmason.com/2016/09/19/Complicated-flowcharts-Scottish-Rite-edition.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Freemason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Free]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mason]]></category><category><![CDATA[Masonry]]></category><category><![CDATA[Craft]]></category><category><![CDATA[Blue]]></category><category><![CDATA[Lodge]]></category><category><![CDATA[Scottish Rite]]></category><category><![CDATA[Charts]]></category><category><![CDATA[Evolution]]></category><pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>